[
{"Front": "嗚呼", "Back": "Ah!;Oh!;Alas!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相", "Back": "together;mutually;fellow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相変わらず", "Back": "as ever;as usual;the same", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愛想", "Back": "civility;courtesy;compliments;sociability;graces", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相対", "Back": "confrontation;facing;between ourselves;no third party;tete-a-tete", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間柄", "Back": "relation(ship)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愛憎", "Back": "likes and dislikes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合間", "Back": "interval", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "曖昧", "Back": "vague;ambiguous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敢えて", "Back": "dare (to do);challenge (to do)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仰ぐ", "Back": "to look up (to);to respect;to depend on;to ask for;to seek;to revere;to drink;to take", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "垢", "Back": "dirt;filth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "亜科", "Back": "suborder;subfamily", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "銅", "Back": "copper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "証", "Back": "proof;evidence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "赤字", "Back": "deficit;go in the red", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明かす", "Back": "to pass;spend;to reveal;to divulge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "赤ちゃん", "Back": "baby;infant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明白", "Back": "obvious;overt;plainly;frankly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "赤らむ", "Back": "to become red;to redden;to blush", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明るい", "Back": "bright;cheerful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上がり", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;slope;advance income;crop yield;ascent;rise;advance;death;spinning;completion;stop;finish;after", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上がる", "Back": "to enter;to go up;to rise;to climb up;to advance;to appreciate;to be promoted;to improve;to call on;", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "商人", "Back": "trader;shopkeeper;merchant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空間", "Back": "vacancy;room for rent or lease", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "諦め", "Back": "resignation;acceptance;consolation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呆れる", "Back": "to be amazed;to be shocked", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪", "Back": "evil;wickedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "灰", "Back": "puckery juice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あくどい", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;gaudy;showy;excessive; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;vicious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪日", "Back": "unlucky day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明くる", "Back": "next;following", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憧れ", "Back": "yearning;longing;aspiration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "顎", "Back": "chin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "麻", "Back": "flax;linen;hemp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明後日", "Back": "day after tomorrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "朝寝坊", "Back": "oversleeping;late riser", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浅ましい", "Back": "wretched;miserable;shameful;mean;despicable;abject", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "字", "Back": "section of village", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欺く", "Back": "to deceive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鮮やか", "Back": "vivid;clear;brilliant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あざ笑う", "Back": "to sneer at;to ridicule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "味わい", "Back": "flavour;meaning;significance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "東", "Back": "east;Eastern Japan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "焦る", "Back": "to be in a hurry;to be impatient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "彼処", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;(uk) there;over there;that place; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;(X) (col) genitals", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "値", "Back": "value;price;cost;worth;merit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "値する", "Back": "to be worth;to deserve;to merit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "私", "Back": "I (fem)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当たり", "Back": "hit;success;reaching the mark;per ...;vicinity;neighborhood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当たり前", "Back": "usual;common;ordinary;natural;reasonable;obvious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "他人", "Back": "another person;unrelated person;outsider;stranger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "彼方此方", "Back": "here and there", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "彼方", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;there;yonder;that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪化", "Back": "deterioration;growing worse;aggravation;degeneration;corruption", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呆気ない", "Back": "not enough;too quick (short&nbsp;&nbsp;long&nbsp;&nbsp;etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪口", "Back": "abuse;insult;slander;evil speaking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あっさり", "Back": "easily;readily;quickly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "圧迫", "Back": "pressure;coercion;oppression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "扱い", "Back": "treatment;service", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "集まる", "Back": "to gather;to collect;to assemble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誂える", "Back": "to give an order;to place an order", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "圧力", "Back": "stress;pressure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当て", "Back": "object;aim;end;hopes;expectations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宛", "Back": "addressed to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当て字", "Back": "phonetic-equivalent character;substitute character", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当てはまる", "Back": "to apply (a rule)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当てはめる", "Back": "to apply;to adapt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宛てる", "Back": "to address", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "跡継ぎ", "Back": "heir;successor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "後回し", "Back": "putting off;postponing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貴女", "Back": "you;lady", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "彼の", "Back": "that over there", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溢れる", "Back": "to flood;to overflow;to brim over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "油絵", "Back": "oil painting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "炙る", "Back": "to scorch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あべこべ", "Back": "contrary;opposite;inverse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "甘える", "Back": "to behave like a spoiled child;to fawn on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "甘口", "Back": "sweet flavour;mildness;flattery;stupidity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雨具", "Back": "rain gear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天", "Back": "heavenly;imperial", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "網", "Back": "net;network", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天地", "Back": "heaven and earth;the universe;nature;top and bottom;realm;sphere;world", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "操る", "Back": "to manipulate;to operate;to pull strings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あやふや", "Back": "uncertain;vague;ambiguous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "危ぶむ", "Back": "to fear;to have misgivings;to be doubtful;to mistrust", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過ち", "Back": "fault;error;indiscretion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誤る", "Back": "to make a mistake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歩み", "Back": "walking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歩む", "Back": "to walk;to go on foot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あら", "Back": "oh;ah;saw-edged perch (Niphon spinosus)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予め", "Back": "beforehand;in advance;previously", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "荒らす", "Back": "to lay waste;to devastate;to damage;to invade;to break into", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粗筋", "Back": "outline;summary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "争い", "Back": "dispute;strife;quarrel;dissension;conflict;rivalry;contest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改まる", "Back": "to be renewed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "荒っぽい", "Back": "rough;rude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凡ゆる", "Back": "all;every", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あられ", "Back": "kind of cookie;cartoon character", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現われ", "Back": "embodiment;materialization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現われる", "Back": "to appear;to come in sight;to become visible;to come out;to embody;to materialize;to express oneself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有難う", "Back": "Thank you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有様", "Back": "state;condition;circumstances;the way things are or should be;truth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有りのまま", "Back": "the truth;fact;as it is;frankly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "或る", "Back": "a certain...;some...", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "或いは", "Back": "or;possibly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "彼此", "Back": "one thing or another;this and that;this or that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合わす", "Back": "to join together;to face;to unite;to be opposite;to combine;to connect;to add up;to mix;to match;to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合わせ", "Back": "joint together;opposite;facing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慌ただしい", "Back": "busy;hurried;confused;flurried", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慌てる", "Back": "to become confused (disconcerted&nbsp;&nbsp;disorganized)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暗殺", "Back": "assassination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暗算", "Back": "mental arithmetic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暗示", "Back": "hint;suggestion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "案じる", "Back": "to be anxious;to ponder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "安静", "Back": "rest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "案の定", "Back": "sure enough;as usual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余り", "Back": "not very (this form only used as adverb);not much;remainder;rest;remnant;surplus;balance;excess;rema", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "依", "Back": "depending on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "良い", "Back": "good", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伊井", "Back": "that one;Italy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "否", "Back": "no;nay;yes;well", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いい加減", "Back": "moderate;right;random;not thorough;vague;irresponsible;halfhearted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言い訳", "Back": "excuse;explanation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家出", "Back": "running away from home;leaving home", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家主", "Back": "landlord", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "如何", "Back": "how;in what way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生かす", "Back": "to revive;to resuscitate;to make use of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雷", "Back": "thunder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "如何に", "Back": "how?;in what way?;how much?;however;whatever", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "如何にも", "Back": "indeed;really;phrase meaning agreement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怒り", "Back": "anger;hatred", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怒る", "Back": "to get angry;to be angry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歪む", "Back": "to warp;to swerve;to deflect;to be crooked;to be distorted;to be bent;to incline;to slant;to be perv", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粋", "Back": "chic;style;purity;essence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "域外", "Back": "outside the area", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意気込む", "Back": "to be enthusiastic about", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経緯", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;details;whole story;sequence of events;particulars;how it started;how things got this way; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;c", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行き違い", "Back": "misunderstanding;estrangement;disagreement;crossing without meeting;going astray", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行き成り", "Back": "suddenly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "異議", "Back": "objection;dissent;protest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いく", "Back": "to come;to orgasm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軍", "Back": "war;battle;campaign;fight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戦", "Back": "war;battle;campaign;fight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "育成", "Back": "rearing;training;nurture;cultivation;promotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幾多", "Back": "many;numerous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "活ける", "Back": "to arrange (flowers)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "異見", "Back": "different opinion;objection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意向", "Back": "intention;idea;inclination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "移行", "Back": "switching over to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いざ", "Back": "now;come (now);well;crucial moment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "碑", "Back": "stone monument bearing an inscription", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衣装", "Back": "clothing;costume;outfit;garment;dress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意地", "Back": "disposition;spirit;willpower;obstinacy;backbone;appetite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苛める", "Back": "to tease;to torment;to persecute;to chastise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "移住", "Back": "migration;immigration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弄る", "Back": "to touch;to tamper with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何れ", "Back": "where;which;who;anyway;anyhow;at any rate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "異性", "Back": "the opposite sex", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遺跡", "Back": "historic ruins (remains&nbsp;&nbsp;relics)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "依然", "Back": "still;as yet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "依存", "Back": "dependence;dependent;reliance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "委託", "Back": "consign (goods (for sale) to a firm);entrust (person with something);commit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪戯", "Back": "tease;prank;trick;practical joke;mischief", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頂", "Back": "(top of) head;summit;spire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戴きます", "Back": "expression of gratitude before meals", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "至って", "Back": "very much;exceedingly;extremely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "痛む", "Back": "to hurt;to feel a pain;to be injured", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "痛める", "Back": "to hurt;to injure;to cause pain;to worry;to bother;to afflict;to be grieved over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "炒める", "Back": "to stir-fry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "労る", "Back": "to pity;to sympathize with;to console;to care for;to be kind to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "市", "Back": "market;fair", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "位地", "Back": "place;situation;position;location", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一々", "Back": "one by one;separately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一概に", "Back": "unconditionally;as a rule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一見", "Back": "unfamiliar;never before met", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一言", "Back": "single word", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一日", "Back": "(1) one day, (2) first of month", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一定", "Back": "fixed;settled;definite;uniform;regularized;defined;standardized;certain;prescribed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "著しい", "Back": "remarkable;considerable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一同", "Back": "all present;all concerned;all of us", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一人", "Back": "one person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一部", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;one copy&nbsp;&nbsp;e.g. of a document; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;a part;partly;some", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一部分", "Back": "a part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一別", "Back": "parting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一面", "Back": "one side;one phase;front page;the other hand;the whole surface", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一目", "Back": "a glance;a look;a glimpse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一様", "Back": "uniformity;evenness;similarity;equality;impartiality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一律", "Back": "evenness;uniformity;monotony;equality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一連", "Back": "a series;a chain;a ream (of paper)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一括", "Back": "all together;batch;one lump;one bundle;summing up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一気", "Back": "drink!(said repeatedly as a party cheer)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一挙に", "Back": "at a stroke;with a single swoop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一切", "Back": "all;everything;without exception;the whole;entirely;absolutely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一心", "Back": "one mind;wholeheartedness;the whole heart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いっそ", "Back": "rather;sooner;might as well", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一帯", "Back": "a region;a zone;the whole place", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一敗", "Back": "one defeat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一変", "Back": "complete change;about-face", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何時", "Back": "when;how soon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何時か", "Back": "sometime;someday;one day;some time or other;the other day;in due course;in time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何時でも", "Back": "(at) any time;always;at all times;never (neg);whenever", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何時の間にか", "Back": "before one knows;unnoticed;unawares", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何時までも", "Back": "forever;for good;eternally;as long as one likes;indefinitely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何時も", "Back": "always;usually;every time;never (with neg. verb)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意図", "Back": "intention;aim;design", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "営む", "Back": "to carry on (e.g. in ceremony);to run a business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暇", "Back": "free time;leisure;leave;spare time;farewell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "異動", "Back": "a change", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "挑む", "Back": "to challenge;to contend for;to make love to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "稲光", "Back": "(flash of) lightning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "古", "Back": "antiquity;ancient times", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祈り", "Back": "prayer;supplication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鼾", "Back": "snoring", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "今更", "Back": "now;at this late hour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未だ", "Back": "as yet;hitherto;not yet (neg)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "移民", "Back": "emigration;immigration;emigrant;immigrant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "厭々", "Back": "unwillingly;grudgingly;shaking head in refusal (to children)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "卑しい", "Back": "greedy;vulgar;shabby;humble;base;mean;vile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いやに", "Back": "awfully;terribly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "厭やらしい", "Back": "detestable;disagreeable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愈々", "Back": "more and more;all the more;increasingly;at last;beyond doubt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意欲", "Back": "will;desire;ambition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苛々", "Back": "getting nervous;irritation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入口", "Back": "entrance;gate;approach;mouth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衣料", "Back": "clothing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "威力", "Back": "power;might;authority;influence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入る", "Back": "to get in;to go in;to come in;to flow into;to set;to set in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衣類", "Back": "clothes;clothing;garments", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "色々", "Back": "various", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "異論", "Back": "different opinion;objection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所謂", "Back": "the so-called;so to speak", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "印", "Back": "seal;stamp;mark;print", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "員", "Back": "member", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "印鑑", "Back": "stamp;seal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "陰気", "Back": "gloom;melancholy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "隠居", "Back": "retirement;retired person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上下", "Back": "high and low;up and down;unloading and loading;praising and blaming", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浮かぶ", "Back": "to float;to rise to surface;to come to mind", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受かる", "Back": "to pass (examination)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "含嗽", "Back": "gargle;rinse mouth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受け入れ", "Back": "receiving;acceptance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受け入れる", "Back": "to accept;to receive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受け継ぐ", "Back": "to inherit;to succeed;to take over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受け付ける", "Back": "to be accepted;to receive (an application)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受け止める", "Back": "to catch;to stop the blow;to react to;to take", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受け取り", "Back": "receipt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受身", "Back": "passive;passive voice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動き", "Back": "movement;activity;trend;development;change", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "潮", "Back": "tide", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "氏", "Back": "family name", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "渦", "Back": "swirl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "埋まる", "Back": "to be buried;to be surrounded;to overflow;to be filled", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嘘つき", "Back": "liar (sometimes said with not much seriousness);fibber", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打ち合わせ", "Back": "business meeting;previous arrangement;appointment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打ち合わせる", "Back": "to knock together;to arrange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打ち切る", "Back": "to stop;to abort;to discontinue;to close", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打ち消し", "Back": "negation;denial;negative", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打ち込む", "Back": "to drive in (e.g. nail&nbsp;&nbsp;stake);to devote oneself to;to shoot into;to smash;to throw into;to cast int", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "団扇", "Back": "fan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内訳", "Back": "the items;breakdown;classification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訴え", "Back": "lawsuit;complaint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鬱陶しい", "Back": "gloomy;depressing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "写し", "Back": "copy;duplicate;facsimile;transcript", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空ろ", "Back": "blank;cavity;hollow;empty (space)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "器", "Back": "bowl;vessel;container", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雨天", "Back": "rainy weather", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腕前", "Back": "ability;skill;facility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "饂飩", "Back": "noodles (Japanese)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "促す", "Back": "to urge;to press;to suggest;to demand;to stimulate;to quicken;to incite;to invite (attention to)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "唸る", "Back": "to groan;to moan;to roar;to howl;to growl;to hum;to buzz;to sough", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自惚れ", "Back": "pretension;conceit;hubris", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "甘い", "Back": "delicious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生まれつき", "Back": "by nature;by birth;native", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "海路", "Back": "sea route", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "産む", "Back": "to give birth;to deliver;to produce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "埋め込む", "Back": "to bury", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "梅干", "Back": "dried plum", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "末", "Back": "top end;tip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裏返し", "Back": "inside out;upside down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売り出し", "Back": "(bargain) sale", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売り出す", "Back": "to put on sale;to market;to become popular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "潤う", "Back": "to be moist;to be damp;to get wet;to profit by;to be watered;to receive benefits;to favor;to charm;t", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "五月蝿い", "Back": "noisy;loud;fussy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売れ行き", "Back": "sales", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浮気", "Back": "flighty;fickle;wanton;unfaithful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上手", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;upper part;upper stream;left side (of a stage); 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;skillful (only in comparisons);dexterity (on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上回る", "Back": "to exceed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "植わる", "Back": "to be planted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運営", "Back": "management;administration;operation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うんざり", "Back": "tedious;boring;being fed up with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運送", "Back": "shipping;marine transportation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運賃", "Back": "freight rates;shipping expenses;fare", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "云々", "Back": "and so on;and so forth;comment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運搬", "Back": "transport;carriage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運命", "Back": "fate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運輸", "Back": "transportation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運用", "Back": "making use of;application;investment;practical use", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "会", "Back": "understanding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重", "Back": "-fold;-ply", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "えい", "Back": "ray (fish)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "映写", "Back": "projection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "英字", "Back": "English letter (character)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衛生", "Back": "health;hygiene;sanitation;medical", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "映像", "Back": "reflection;image", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "英雄", "Back": "hero;great man", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "液", "Back": "liquid;fluid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役", "Back": "war;campaign;battle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "閲覧", "Back": "inspection;reading", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "獲物", "Back": "game;spoils;trophy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "襟", "Back": "neck;collar;lapel;neckband", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縁", "Back": "chance;fate;destiny;relation;bonds;connection;karma", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塩", "Back": "salt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "艶", "Back": "charming;fascinating;voluptuous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "園", "Back": "garden (esp. man-made)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "円滑", "Back": "harmony;smoothness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縁側", "Back": "veranda;porch;balcony;open corridor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沿岸", "Back": "coast;shore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "婉曲", "Back": "euphemistic;circumlocution;roundabout;indirect;insinuating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "演習", "Back": "practice;exercises;manoeuvers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "演出", "Back": "production (e.g. play);direction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "演じる", "Back": "to perform (a play);to play (a part);to act (a part);to commit (a blunder)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "演ずる", "Back": "to perform;to play", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沿線", "Back": "along railway line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縁談", "Back": "marriage proposal;engagement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遠方", "Back": "long way;distant place", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "円満", "Back": "perfection;harmony;peace;smoothness;completeness;satisfaction;integrity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尾", "Back": "tail;ridge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "於", "Back": "at;in;on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "甥", "Back": "nephew", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追い込む", "Back": "to herd;to corner;to drive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "美味しい", "Back": "delicious;tasty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追い出す", "Back": "to expel;to drive out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "於いて", "Back": "at;in;on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お出でになる", "Back": "to be", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "老いる", "Back": "to age;to grow old", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "負う", "Back": "to bear;to owe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "応急", "Back": "emergency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "黄金", "Back": "gold", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "黄色", "Back": "yellow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "応募", "Back": "subscription;application", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おおい", "Back": "hey!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大方", "Back": "perhaps;almost all;majority", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大柄", "Back": "large build;large pattern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大げさ", "Back": "grandiose;exaggerated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大事", "Back": "important;valuable;serious matter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大ざっぱ", "Back": "rough (as in not precise);broad;sketchy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大筋", "Back": "outline;summary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大空", "Back": "heaven;firmament;the sky", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大幅", "Back": "full width;large scale;drastic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大水", "Back": "flood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公", "Back": "official;public;formal;open;governmental", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お蔭", "Back": "(your) backing;assistance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お蔭様で", "Back": "Thanks to god;thanks to you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可笑しい", "Back": "strange;funny;amusing;ridiculous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "犯す", "Back": "to commit;to perpetrate;to violate;to rape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "侵す", "Back": "to invade;to raid;to trespass;to violate;to intrude on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お菜", "Back": "side dish;accompaniment for rice dishes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "臆病", "Back": "cowardice;timidity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遅らす", "Back": "to retard;to delay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遅れ", "Back": "delay;lag", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "起こす", "Back": "to raise;to cause;to wake someone", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行い", "Back": "deed;conduct;behavior;action;asceticism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "厳か", "Back": "austere;majestic;dignified;stately;awful;impressive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傲る", "Back": "to be proud", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長", "Back": "chief;head", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "押さえる", "Back": "to stop;to restrain;to seize;to repress;to suppress;to press down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お先に", "Back": "before;ahead;previously", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "収まる", "Back": "to be obtained;to end;to settle into;to fit into;to be settled;to be paid;to be delivered", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "納まる", "Back": "to be obtained;to end;to settle into;to fit into;to be settled;to be paid;to be delivered", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "治まる", "Back": "to be at peace;to clamp down;to lessen (storm&nbsp;&nbsp;terror&nbsp;&nbsp;anger)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お産", "Back": "(giving) birth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教え", "Back": "teachings;precept;lesson;doctrine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "押し込む", "Back": "to push into;to crowd into", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "惜しむ", "Back": "to be frugal;to value;to regret", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お喋り", "Back": "chattering;talk;idle talk;chat;chitchat;gossip;chatty;talkative;chatterbox;blabbermouth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お洒落", "Back": "smartly dressed;someone smartly dressed;fashion-conscious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "押し寄せる", "Back": "to push aside;to advance on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お祖父さん", "Back": "grandfather;male senior-citizen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お邪魔します", "Back": "Excuse me for disturbing (interrupting) you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雄", "Back": "male (animal)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お世辞", "Back": "flattery;compliment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "襲う", "Back": "to attack", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遅くとも", "Back": "at the latest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恐らく", "Back": "perhaps", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恐れ", "Back": "fear;horror", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恐れ入る", "Back": "to be filled with awe;to feel small;to be amazed;to be surprised;to be disconcerted;to be sorry;to b", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お大事に", "Back": "Take care of yourself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煽てる", "Back": "to stir up;to instigate;to flatter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落ち込む", "Back": "to fall into;to feel down (sad)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落ち着き", "Back": "calm;composure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落ち葉", "Back": "fallen leaves;leaf litter;defoliation;shedding leaves", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落ちる", "Back": "to fail (e.g. exam);to fall down;to drop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おっかない", "Back": "frightening;huge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仰っしゃる", "Back": "to say;to speak;to tell;to talk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乙", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;strange;quaint;stylish;chic;spicy;queer;witty;tasty;romantic; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;2nd in rank;second sign of the", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お使い", "Back": "errand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お手上げ", "Back": "all over;given in;given up hope;bring to knees", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御手洗い", "Back": "toilet;restroom;lavatory;bathroom (US)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弟", "Back": "younger brother", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落とす", "Back": "to drop;to lose;to let fall", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訪れる", "Back": "to visit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大人しい", "Back": "obedient;docile;quiet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "少女", "Back": "daughter;young lady;virgin;maiden;little girl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お供", "Back": "attendant;companion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衰える", "Back": "to become weak;to decline;to wear;to abate;to decay;to wither;to waste away", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おどおど", "Back": "coweringly;hesitantly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脅かす", "Back": "to threaten;to coerce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脅す", "Back": "to threaten;to menace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "驚き", "Back": "surprise;astonishment;wonder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同い年", "Back": "of the same age", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "女子", "Back": "woman;girl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お願いします", "Back": "please", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "各", "Back": "each;every;either;respectively;severally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自ずから", "Back": "naturally;as a matter of course", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お早う", "Back": "Good morning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お祖母さん", "Back": "grandmother;female senior-citizen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怯える", "Back": "to become frightened;to have a nightmare", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夥しい", "Back": "abundantly;innumerably", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "帯びる", "Back": "to wear;to carry;to be entrusted;to have;to take on;to have a trace of;to be tinged with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "覚え", "Back": "memory;sense;experience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御負け", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;a discount;a prize; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;something additional;bonus;an extra; 3.&nbsp;&nbsp;an exaggeration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お巡りさん", "Back": "policeman (friendly term)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お宮", "Back": "Shinto shrine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お襁褓", "Back": "diaper;nappy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お目出度う", "Back": "(ateji) (int) (uk) Congratulations!;an auspicious occasion!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面", "Back": "face", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思い付き", "Back": "plan;idea;suggestion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面白い", "Back": "interesting;amusing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "玩具", "Back": "toy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重なる", "Back": "main;principal;important", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "趣", "Back": "meaning;tenor;gist;effect;appearance;taste;grace;charm;refinement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "赴く", "Back": "to go;to proceed;to repair to;to become", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重役", "Back": "heavy responsibilities;director", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重んじる", "Back": "to respect;to honor;to esteem;to prize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重んずる", "Back": "to honor;to respect;to esteem;to prize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お休み", "Back": "holiday;absence;rest;Good night", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お八", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;(uk) between meal snack;afternoon refreshment;afternoon tea; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;mid-day snack", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凡そ", "Back": "about;roughly;as a rule;approximately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "及び", "Back": "and;as well as", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "及ぶ", "Back": "to reach;to come up to;to amount to;to befall;to happen to;to extend;to match;to equal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "織", "Back": "weave;weaving;woven item", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "檻", "Back": "cage;pen;jail cell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "折り返す", "Back": "to turn up;to fold back", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "織物", "Back": "textile;fabric", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "織る", "Back": "to weave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "俺", "Back": "I (ego) (boastful first-person pronoun)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愚か", "Back": "foolish;stupid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "疎か", "Back": "neglect;negligence;carelessness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "終わる", "Back": "to finish;to close", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "音色", "Back": "tone color;tone quality;timbre;synthesizer patch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "温和", "Back": "gentle;mild;moderate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仮", "Back": "tentative;provisional", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "科", "Back": "department;section", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "個", "Back": "article counter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下位", "Back": "low rank;subordinate;lower order (e.g. byte)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "階", "Back": "-floor (counter);stories", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改悪", "Back": "deterioration;changing for the worse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "海運", "Back": "maritime;marine transportation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改革", "Back": "reform;reformation;innovation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貝殻", "Back": "shell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "階級", "Back": "class;rank;grade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "海峡", "Back": "channel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "会見", "Back": "interview;audience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "介護", "Back": "nursing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "開催", "Back": "holding a meeting;open an exhibition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回収", "Back": "collection;recovery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改修", "Back": "repair;improvement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怪獣", "Back": "monster", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解除", "Back": "cancellation;rescinding;release;calling off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回送", "Back": "forwarding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "階層", "Back": "class;level;stratum;hierarchy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "開拓", "Back": "reclamation (of wasteland);cultivation;pioneer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "会談", "Back": "conversation;conference;discussion;interview", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改定", "Back": "reform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改訂", "Back": "revision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "街道", "Back": "highway", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "介入", "Back": "intervention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "開発", "Back": "development;exploitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "海抜", "Back": "height above sea level", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "介抱", "Back": "nursing;looking after", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解剖", "Back": "dissection;autopsy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回覧", "Back": "circulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "海流", "Back": "ocean current", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改良", "Back": "improvement;reform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回路", "Back": "circuit (electric)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "顧みる", "Back": "to look back;to turn around;to review", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "省みる", "Back": "to reflect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "返る", "Back": "to return;to come back;to go back", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "顔付き", "Back": "(outward) looks;features;face;countenance;expression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掲げる", "Back": "to publish;to print;to carry (an article);to put up;to hang out;to hoist;to fly (a sail);to float (a", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "踵", "Back": "(shoe) heel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "係り", "Back": "official;duty;person in charge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "課外", "Back": "extracurricular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書き取り", "Back": "dictation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書き取る", "Back": "to write down;to take dictation;to take notes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掻き回す", "Back": "to stir up;to churn;to ransack;to disturb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欠く", "Back": "to lack;to break;to crack;to chip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "角", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;angle; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;bishop (shogi)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "核", "Back": "nucleus;kernel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "格", "Back": "status;character;case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "佳句", "Back": "beautiful passage of literature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "画", "Back": "stroke", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "格差", "Back": "qualitative difference;disparity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拡散", "Back": "scattering;diffusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "各種", "Back": "every kind;all sorts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "隔週", "Back": "every other week", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確信", "Back": "conviction;confidence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "革新", "Back": "reform;innovation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確定", "Back": "definition (math);decision;settlement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "獲得", "Back": "acquisition;possession", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確保", "Back": "guarantee;ensure;maintain;insure;secure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "革命", "Back": "revolution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確立", "Back": "establishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賭け", "Back": "betting;gambling;a gamble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掛け", "Back": "credit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "駆け足", "Back": "running fast;double time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家計", "Back": "household economy;family finances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "駆けっこ", "Back": "(foot) race", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "駆ける", "Back": "to run (race&nbsp;&nbsp;esp. horse);to gallop;to canter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賭ける", "Back": "to wager;to bet;to risk;to stake;to gamble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ヶ月", "Back": "#NAME?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加工", "Back": "manufacturing;processing;treatment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "化合", "Back": "chemical combination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嵩張る", "Back": "to be bulky;to be unwieldy;to grow voluminous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嵩む", "Back": "to pile up;to increase", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "風車", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;windmill; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;pinwheel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "畏まりました", "Back": "certainly!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "華奢", "Back": "luxury;pomp;delicate;slender;gorgeous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "箇所", "Back": "passage;place;point;part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火傷", "Back": "burn;scald", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "箇条書き", "Back": "itemized form;itemization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "噛る", "Back": "to chew;to bite (at);to gnaw;to nibble;to munch;to crunch;to have a smattering of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "微か", "Back": "faint;dim;weak;indistinct;hazy;poor;wretched", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "霞む", "Back": "to grow hazy;to be misty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "化する", "Back": "to change into;to convert into;to transform;to be reduced;to influence;to improve (someone)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "擦る", "Back": "to touch lightly;to take a percentage (from)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火星", "Back": "Mars (planet)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "化石", "Back": "fossil;petrifaction;fossilization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "河川", "Back": "rivers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "化繊", "Back": "synthetic fibres", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過疎", "Back": "depopulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過多", "Back": "excess;superabundance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "難い", "Back": "difficult;hard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "片思い", "Back": "unrequited love", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敵", "Back": "enemy;rival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気質", "Back": "spirit;character;trait;temperament;disposition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "片言", "Back": "a smattering;talk like a baby;speak haltingly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "片付け", "Back": "tidying up;finishing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傾く", "Back": "to incline toward;to slant;to lurch;to heel over;to be disposed to;to trend toward;to be prone to;to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傾ける", "Back": "to incline;to list;to bend;to lean;to tip;to tilt;to slant;to concentrate on;to ruin (a country);to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "固める", "Back": "to harden;to freeze;to fortify", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偏る", "Back": "to be one-sided;to incline;to be partial;to be prejudiced;to lean;to be biased", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傍ら", "Back": "beside(s);while;nearby", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "課題", "Back": "subject;theme;task", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "花壇", "Back": "flower bed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家畜", "Back": "domestic animals;livestock;cattle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "画期", "Back": "epoch-making", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "活発", "Back": "vigor;active", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "且つ", "Back": "yet;and", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割", "Back": "divide;cut;halve;separate;split;rip;break;crack;smash;dilute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嘗て", "Back": "once;ever", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日付", "Back": "date;dating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "門", "Back": "gate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "叶う", "Back": "to come true (wish)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "叶える", "Back": "to grant (request&nbsp;&nbsp;wish)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金槌", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;(iron) hammer; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;punishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉄棒", "Back": "iron rod;crowbar;horizontal bar (gymnastics)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可成", "Back": "considerably;fairly;quite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加入", "Back": "becoming a member;joining;entry;admission;subscription;affiliation;adherence;signing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金庫", "Back": "safe;vault;treasury;provider of funds", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予言", "Back": "prediction;promise;prognostication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兼ねて", "Back": "simultaneously", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下番", "Back": "going off duty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下品", "Back": "inferior article", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "華美", "Back": "pomp;splendor;gaudiness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "花粉", "Back": "pollen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "株式", "Back": "stock (company)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気触れる", "Back": "to react to;to be influenced by;to go overboard for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貨幣", "Back": "money;currency;coinage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "構え", "Back": "posture;pose;style", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "構える", "Back": "to set up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加味", "Back": "seasoning;flavoring", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "噛み切る", "Back": "to bite off;to gnaw through", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過密", "Back": "crowded", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瓶", "Back": "earthenware pot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かも知れない", "Back": "may;might;perhaps;may be;possibly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粥", "Back": "(rice) gruel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "痒い", "Back": "itchy;itching", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揶揄う", "Back": "to ridicule;to tease;to banter with;to make fun of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "身体", "Back": "the body", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体付き", "Back": "body build;figure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絡む", "Back": "to entangle;to entwine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "借り", "Back": "borrowing;debt;loan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下吏", "Back": "lower official", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加留多", "Back": "(pt:) (n) playing cards (pt: carta)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "涸れる", "Back": "to dry up;to run out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過労", "Back": "overwork;strain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辛うじて", "Back": "barely;narrowly;just manage to do st", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "側", "Back": "side;row;surroundings;part;(watch) case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可愛い", "Back": "pretty;cute;lovely;charming;dear;darling;pet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可愛がる", "Back": "to love;to be affectionate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可哀想", "Back": "poor;pitiable;pathetic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可愛らしい", "Back": "lovely;sweet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交わす", "Back": "to exchange (messages);to dodge;to parry;to avoid;to turn aside", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代わる", "Back": "to take the place of;to relieve;to be substituted for;to be exchanged;to change places with;to take", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代わる代わる", "Back": "alternately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乾", "Back": "heaven;emperor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "管", "Back": "pipe;tube", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幹", "Back": "(tree) trunk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冠", "Back": "crown;diadem;first;best;peerless;cap;naming;designating;initiating on coming of age;top character ra", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観", "Back": "look;appearance;spectacle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "館", "Back": "house;hall;building;hotel;inn;guesthouse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "簡易", "Back": "simplicity;easiness;quasi-", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感慨", "Back": "strong feelings;deep emotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寒気", "Back": "cold;frost;chill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "簡潔", "Back": "brevity;conciseness;simplicity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "還元", "Back": "resolution;reduction;return to origins", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刊行", "Back": "publication;issue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慣行", "Back": "customary practice;habit;traditional event", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勧告", "Back": "advice;counsel;remonstrance;recommendation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "看護", "Back": "nursing;(army) nurse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漢語", "Back": "Chinese word;Sino-Japanese word", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "換算", "Back": "conversion;change;exchange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "監視", "Back": "observation;guarding;inspection;surveillance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慣習", "Back": "usual (historical) custom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観衆", "Back": "spectators;onlookers;members of the audience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "干渉", "Back": "interference;intervention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感触", "Back": "sense of touch;feeling;sensation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肝心", "Back": "essential;fundamental;crucial;vital;main", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歓声", "Back": "cheer;shout of joy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感染", "Back": "infection;contagion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幹線", "Back": "main line;trunk line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "関税", "Back": "customs;duty;tariff", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "簡素", "Back": "simplicity;plain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観点", "Back": "point of view", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感度", "Back": "sensitivity;severity (quake)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幹部", "Back": "management;(executive) staff;leaders", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勘弁", "Back": "pardon;forgiveness;forbearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "完璧", "Back": "perfection;completeness;flawless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感無量", "Back": "deep feeling;inexpressible feeling;filled with emotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勧誘", "Back": "invitation;solicitation;canvassing;inducement;persuasion;encouragement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "関与", "Back": "participation;taking part in;participating in;being concerned in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慣用", "Back": "common;customary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寛容", "Back": "forbearance;tolerance;generosity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観覧", "Back": "viewing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "官僚", "Back": "bureaucrat;bureaucracy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慣例", "Back": "custom;precedent;of convention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "還暦", "Back": "60th birthday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貫禄", "Back": "presence;dignity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "緩和", "Back": "relief;mitigation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蓋", "Back": "cover;lid;cap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "街", "Back": "~street;~quarters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外貨", "Back": "imported goods;foreign money", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外観", "Back": "appearance;exterior;facade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外相", "Back": "Foreign Minister", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "害する", "Back": "to injure;to damage;to harm;to kill;to hinder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "概説", "Back": "general statement;outline", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "該当", "Back": "corresponding;answering to;coming under", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "街頭", "Back": "in the street", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "概念", "Back": "general idea;concept;notion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外来", "Back": "imported;outpatient clinic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "概略", "Back": "outline;summary;gist;in brief", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学芸", "Back": "arts and sciences;liberal arts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学士", "Back": "university graduate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学説", "Back": "theory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "楽譜", "Back": "score (music)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学歴", "Back": "academic background", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "崖", "Back": "cliff", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雅致", "Back": "artistry;good taste;elegance;grace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "がっくり", "Back": "heartbroken", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合唱", "Back": "chorus;singing in a chorus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "がっしり", "Back": "firmly;solidly;tough", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合致", "Back": "agreement;concurrence;conforming to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "がっちり", "Back": "solidly built;tightly;shrewd;calculating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月日", "Back": "(the) date", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合併", "Back": "combination;union;amalgamation;consolidation;merger;coalition;fusion;annexation;affiliation;incorpor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "がる", "Back": "feel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "癌", "Back": "cancer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "眼科", "Back": "ophthalmology", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "眼球", "Back": "eyeball", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "眼鏡", "Back": "spectacles;glasses", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頑固", "Back": "stubbornness;obstinacy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "願書", "Back": "written application or petition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頑丈", "Back": "solid;firm;stout;burly;strong;sturdy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "岩石", "Back": "rock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "元年", "Back": "first year (of a specific reign)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "贋物", "Back": "imitation;counterfeit;forgery;sham", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "元来", "Back": "originally;primarily;essentially;logically;naturally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生", "Back": "pure;undiluted;raw;crude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "期", "Back": "period;time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "企画", "Back": "planning;project", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "規格", "Back": "standard;norm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着飾る", "Back": "to dress up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "器官", "Back": "organ (of body);instrument", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "季刊", "Back": "quarterly (e.g. magazine)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "危害", "Back": "injury;harm;danger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気兼ね", "Back": "hesitance;diffidence;feeling constraint;fear of troubling someone;having scruples about doing someth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気軽", "Back": "cheerful;buoyant;lighthearted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "危機", "Back": "crisis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "聞き取り", "Back": "listening comprehension", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "効き目", "Back": "effect;virtue;efficacy;impression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "帰京", "Back": "returning to Tokyo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基金", "Back": "fund;foundation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "棄権", "Back": "abstain from voting;renunciation of a right", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "喜劇", "Back": "comedy;funny show", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "起源", "Back": "origin;beginning;rise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "機構", "Back": "mechanism;organization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "既婚", "Back": "marriage;married", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記載", "Back": "mention;entry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気障", "Back": "affectation;conceit;snobbery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兆し", "Back": "signs;omen;symptoms", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兆", "Back": "signs;omen;symptoms", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軋む", "Back": "to jar;to creak;to grate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気象", "Back": "weather;climate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "期日", "Back": "fixed date;settlement date", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記述", "Back": "describing;descriptor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奇数", "Back": "odd number", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "築く", "Back": "to build;to pile up;to amass", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傷付く", "Back": "to be hurt;to be wounded;to get injured", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "規制", "Back": "regulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汽船", "Back": "steamship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寄贈", "Back": "donation;presentation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貴族", "Back": "noble;aristocrat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鍛える", "Back": "to forge;to drill;to temper;to train;to discipline", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "来る", "Back": "to come;to arrive;to be due to;to be next;to be forthcoming", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気立て", "Back": "disposition;nature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "きちっと", "Back": "exactly;perfectly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "几帳面", "Back": "methodical;punctual;steady", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切っ掛け", "Back": "chance;start;cue;excuse;motive;impetus;occasion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "きっかり", "Back": "exactly;precisely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "喫茶", "Back": "tea drinking;tea house", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "きっちり", "Back": "precisely;tightly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "屹度", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;(uk) surely;undoubtedly;certainly;without fail; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;sternly;severely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "きっぱり", "Back": "clearly;plainly;distinctly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "規定", "Back": "regulation;provisions", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "起点", "Back": "starting point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軌道", "Back": "orbit;railroad track", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "甲", "Back": "1st in rank;first sign of the Chinese calendar;shell;instep;grade A", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気配", "Back": "indication;market trend;worry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "規範", "Back": "model;standard;pattern;norm;criterion;example", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気品", "Back": "aroma", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気風", "Back": "character;traits;ethos", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "起伏", "Back": "undulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "規模", "Back": "scale;scope;plan;structure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気まぐれ", "Back": "whim;caprice;whimsy;fickle;moody;uneven temper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生真面目", "Back": "too serious;person who is too serious;honesty;sincerity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "期末", "Back": "end of term", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決まり悪い", "Back": "feeling awkward;being ashamed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決まる", "Back": "to be decided;to be settled;to look good in (clothes)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記名", "Back": "signature;register", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脚色", "Back": "dramatization (e.g. film)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脚本", "Back": "scenario", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "客観", "Back": "objective", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "規約", "Back": "agreement;rules;code", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "救援", "Back": "relief;rescue;reinforcement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休学", "Back": "temporary absence from school;suspension", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "究極", "Back": "ultimate;final;eventual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "窮屈", "Back": "narrow;tight;stiff;rigid;uneasy;formal;constrained", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "球根", "Back": "(plant) bulb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "救済", "Back": "relief;aid;rescue;salvation;help", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "給食", "Back": "school lunch;providing a meal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "給仕", "Back": "office boy (girl);page;waiter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休戦", "Back": "truce;armistice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "旧知", "Back": "old friend;old friendship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宮殿", "Back": "palace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "窮乏", "Back": "poverty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丘陵", "Back": "hill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共", "Back": "both;neither (neg);all;and;as well as;including;with;together with;plural ending", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "供", "Back": "offer;present;submit;serve (a meal);supply", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "驚異", "Back": "wonder;miracle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教員", "Back": "teaching staff", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教科", "Back": "subject;curriculum", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "協会", "Back": "association;society;organization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共感", "Back": "sympathy;response", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共学", "Back": "coeducation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "協議", "Back": "conference;consultation;discussion;negotiation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教訓", "Back": "lesson;precept;moral instruction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "境遇", "Back": "environment;circumstances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強行", "Back": "forcing;enforcement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強硬", "Back": "firm;vigorous;unbending;unyielding;strong;stubborn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凶作", "Back": "bad harvest;poor crop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共産", "Back": "communism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教材", "Back": "teaching materials", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教習", "Back": "training;instruction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "郷愁", "Back": "nostalgia;homesickness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教職", "Back": "teaching certificate;the teaching profession", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "享受", "Back": "reception;acceptance;enjoyment;being given", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "興じる", "Back": "to amuse oneself;to make merry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強制", "Back": "obligation;coercion;compulsion;enforcement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共存", "Back": "coexistence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "姉妹", "Back": "sisters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "協調", "Back": "co-operation;conciliation;harmony;firm (market) tone", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "協定", "Back": "arrangement;pact;agreement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脅迫", "Back": "threat;menace;coercion;terrorism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共鳴", "Back": "resonance;sympathy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "郷里", "Back": "birth-place;home town", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強烈", "Back": "strong;intense;severe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共和", "Back": "republicanism;cooperation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "曲", "Back": "tune;piece of music", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "局限", "Back": "limit;localize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "極端", "Back": "extreme;extremity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "居住", "Back": "residence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拒絶", "Back": "refusal;rejection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拒否", "Back": "denial;veto;rejection;refusal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "許容", "Back": "permission;pardon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "距離", "Back": "distance;range", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寄与", "Back": "contribution;service", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清らか", "Back": "clean;pure;chaste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気楽", "Back": "at ease;comfortable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煌びやか", "Back": "gorgeous;gaudy;dazzling;gay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切り", "Back": "limits;end;bounds;period;place to leave off;closing sentence;all there is;only;since", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "桐", "Back": "paulownia tree", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切り替える", "Back": "to change;to exchange;to convert;to renew;to throw a switch;to replace;to switch over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気流", "Back": "atmospheric current", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奇麗", "Back": "pretty;clean;nice;tidy;beautiful;fair", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切れ目", "Back": "break;pause;gap;end;rift;interruption;cut;section;notch;incision;end (of a task)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "際", "Back": "edge;brink;verge;side", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "木綿", "Back": "cotton", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "極めて", "Back": "exceedingly;extremely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "僅", "Back": "a little;small quantity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近眼", "Back": "nearsightedness;shortsightedness;myopia", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "緊急", "Back": "urgent;pressing;emergency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近々", "Back": "nearness;before long", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近郊", "Back": "suburbs;outskirts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "均衡", "Back": "equilibrium;balance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近視", "Back": "shortsightedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "禁じる", "Back": "to prohibit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "禁ずる", "Back": "to forbid;to suppress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勤勉", "Back": "industry;diligence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勤務", "Back": "service;duty;work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "禁物", "Back": "taboo;forbidden thing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勤労", "Back": "labor;exertion;diligent service", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "議案", "Back": "legislative bill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戯曲", "Back": "play;drama", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "議決", "Back": "resolution;decision;vote", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "議事堂", "Back": "Diet building", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "犠牲", "Back": "sacrifice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偽造", "Back": "forgery;falsification;fabrication;counterfeiting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "議題", "Back": "topic of discussion;agenda", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "技能", "Back": "technical skill;ability;capacity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逆転", "Back": "(sudden) change;reversal;turn-around;coming from behind (baseball)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行", "Back": "line;row;verse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "業者", "Back": "trader;merchant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行政", "Back": "administration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "業績", "Back": "achievement;performance;results;work;contribution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "業務", "Back": "business;affairs;duties;work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "玉", "Back": "king (shogi)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漁船", "Back": "fishing boat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漁村", "Back": "fishing village", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "義理", "Back": "duty;sense of duty;honor;decency;courtesy;debt of gratitude;social obligation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "疑惑", "Back": "doubt;misgivings;distrust;suspicion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吟味", "Back": "testing;scrutiny;careful investigation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区", "Back": "ward;district;section", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食い違う", "Back": "to cross each other;to run counter to;to differ;to clash;to go awry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空腹", "Back": "hunger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区画", "Back": "division;section;compartment;boundary;area;block", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区間", "Back": "section (of track&nbsp;&nbsp;etc)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "茎", "Back": "stalk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区切り", "Back": "an end;a stop;punctuation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "潜る", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;to drive;to pass through; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;to evade;to hide; 3.&nbsp;&nbsp;to dive (into or under water);to go undergro", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "種々", "Back": "variety", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嚏", "Back": "sneeze", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "旧事", "Back": "past events;bygones", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "籤引", "Back": "lottery;drawn lot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "擽ぐったい", "Back": "ticklish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "草臥れる", "Back": "to get tired;to wear out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下らない", "Back": "good-for-nothing;stupid;trivial;worthless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "件", "Back": "example;precedent;the usual;the said;the above-mentioned;(man) in question", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "口ずさむ", "Back": "to hum something;to sing to oneself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嘴", "Back": "beak;bill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "朽ちる", "Back": "to rot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くっきり", "Back": "distinctly;clearly;boldly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "屈折", "Back": "bending;indentation;refraction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くっ付く", "Back": "to adhere to;to keep close to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くっ付ける", "Back": "to attach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "覆す", "Back": "to overturn;to upset;to overthrow;to undermine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "諄い", "Back": "verbose;importunate;heavy (taste)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国境", "Back": "national or state border", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "首飾り", "Back": "necklace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "首輪", "Back": "necklace;choker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組み合わせ", "Back": "combination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組み合わせる", "Back": "to join together;to combine;to join up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組み込む", "Back": "to insert;to include;to cut in (printing)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蔵", "Back": "warehouse;cellar;magazine;granary;godown;depository;treasury;elevator", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苦しめる", "Back": "to torment;to harass;to inflict pain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "包む", "Back": "to be engulfed in;to be enveloped by;to wrap up;to tuck in;to pack;to do up;to cover with;to dress i", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呉れ呉れも", "Back": "repeatedly;sincerely;earnestly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呉れる", "Back": "to give;to let one have;to do for one;to be given", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "玄人", "Back": "expert;professional;geisha;prostitute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "黒字", "Back": "balance (figure) in the black", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "君主", "Back": "ruler;monarch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愚痴", "Back": "idle complaint;grumble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぐっと", "Back": "firmly;fast;much;more", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぐらい", "Back": "approximately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "群", "Back": "group (math)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軍艦", "Back": "warship;battleship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "群集", "Back": "(social) group;crowd;throng;mob;multitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軍事", "Back": "military affairs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軍備", "Back": "armaments;military preparations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軍服", "Back": "military or naval uniform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刑", "Back": "penalty;sentence;punishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頃", "Back": "time;about;toward;approximately (time)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傾", "Back": "lean;incline", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "系", "Back": "system;lineage;group", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経過", "Back": "passage;expiration;progress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軽快", "Back": "rhythmical (e.g. melody);casual (e.g. dress);light;nimble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "警戒", "Back": "warning;admonition;vigilance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "計器", "Back": "meter;gauge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "契機", "Back": "opportunity;chance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敬具", "Back": "Sincerely yours", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軽減", "Back": "abatement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掲載", "Back": "appearance (e.g. article in paper)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傾斜", "Back": "inclination;slant;slope;bevel;list;dip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "形成", "Back": "formation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "形勢", "Back": "condition;situation;prospects", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軽率", "Back": "rash;thoughtless;careless;hasty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "携帯", "Back": "carrying something", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "形態", "Back": "form;shape;figure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刑罰", "Back": "judgement;penalty;punishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経費", "Back": "expenses;cost;outlay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "警部", "Back": "police inspector", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軽蔑", "Back": "scorn;disdain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経歴", "Back": "personal history;career", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経路", "Back": "course;route;channel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汚す", "Back": "to disgrace;to dishonour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汚らわしい", "Back": "filthy;unfair", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汚れ", "Back": "uncleanness;impurity;disgrace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汚れる", "Back": "to get dirty;to become dirty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "獣", "Back": "beast;brute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吝嗇", "Back": "stinginess;miser;miserliness;skinflint;tightwad;niggard;pinching pennies", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結核", "Back": "tuberculosis;tubercule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "血管", "Back": "blood vessel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決行", "Back": "doing (with resolve);carrying out (i.e. a plan)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決算", "Back": "balance sheet;settlement of accounts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決勝", "Back": "decision of a contest;finals (in sports)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結晶", "Back": "crystal;crystallization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結成", "Back": "formation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結束", "Back": "union;unity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傑", "Back": "excellence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決意", "Back": "decision;determination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決議", "Back": "resolution;vote;decision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結合", "Back": "combination;union", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決断", "Back": "decision;determination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欠乏", "Back": "want;shortage;famine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蹴飛ばす", "Back": "to kick away;to kick off;to kick (someone);to refuse;to reject", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貶す", "Back": "to speak ill of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煙たい", "Back": "smoky;feeling awkward", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煙る", "Back": "to smoke (e.g. fire)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家来", "Back": "retainer;retinue;servant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "けれど", "Back": "but;however", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "圏", "Back": "sphere;circle;range", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "権", "Back": "authority;the right (to do something)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "権威", "Back": "authority;power;influence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兼業", "Back": "side line;second business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "権限", "Back": "power;authority;jurisdiction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "健在", "Back": "in good health;well", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "懸賞", "Back": "offering prizes;winning;reward", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "検事", "Back": "public prosecutor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "健全", "Back": "health;soundness;wholesome", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見地", "Back": "point of view", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賢明", "Back": "wisdom;intelligence;prudence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "倹約", "Back": "thrift;economy;frugality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兼用", "Back": "multi-use;combined use;combination;serving two purposes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "権力", "Back": "power;authority;influence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "劇団", "Back": "troupe;theatrical company", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "激励", "Back": "encouragement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月謝", "Back": "monthly tuition fee", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "げっそり", "Back": "being disheartened;losing weight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月賦", "Back": "monthly installment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下痢", "Back": "diarrhoea", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原", "Back": "original;primitive;primary;fundamental;raw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原形", "Back": "original form;base form", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現行", "Back": "present;current;in operation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原作", "Back": "original work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原子", "Back": "atom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "元首", "Back": "ruler;sovereign", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原書", "Back": "original document", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "減少", "Back": "decrease;reduction;decline", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現場", "Back": "actual spot;scene;scene of the crime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "元素", "Back": "chemical element", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原則", "Back": "principle;general rule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現像", "Back": "developing (film)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現地", "Back": "actual place;local", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "限定", "Back": "limit;restriction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原点", "Back": "origin (coordinates);starting point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原典", "Back": "original (text)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "減点", "Back": "subtract;give a demerit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原爆", "Back": "atomic bomb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原文", "Back": "the text;original", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "厳密", "Back": "strict;close", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原油", "Back": "crude oil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言論", "Back": "discussion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "故", "Back": "the late (deceased)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戸", "Back": "counter for houses", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "児", "Back": "child;the young of animals", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巨", "Back": "big;large;great", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恋する", "Back": "to fall in love with;to love", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溝", "Back": "10^38;hundred undecillion (American);hundred sextillion (British)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "校", "Back": "-school;proof", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好意", "Back": "good will;favor;courtesy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行為", "Back": "act;deed;conduct", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行員", "Back": "bank clerk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交易", "Back": "trade;commerce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公演", "Back": "public performance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "後悔", "Back": "regret;repentance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公開", "Back": "presenting to the public", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "航海", "Back": "sail;voyage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "工学", "Back": "engineering", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "皇居", "Back": "Imperial Palace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好況", "Back": "prosperous conditions;healthy economy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抗議", "Back": "protest;objection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉱業", "Back": "mining industry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "興業", "Back": "industrial enterprise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高原", "Back": "tableland;plateau", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煌々と", "Back": "brilliantly;brightly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "考古学", "Back": "archaeology", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交互", "Back": "mutual;reciprocal;alternate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "工作", "Back": "work;construction;handicraft;maneuvering", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "耕作", "Back": "cultivation;farming", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉱山", "Back": "mine (ore)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "講習", "Back": "short course;training", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交渉", "Back": "negotiations;discussions;connection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高尚", "Back": "high;noble;refined;advanced", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行進", "Back": "march;parade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "香辛料", "Back": "spices", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "口述", "Back": "verbal statement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "控除", "Back": "subsidy;deduction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "向上", "Back": "elevation;rise;improvement;advancement;progress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "降水", "Back": "rainfall;precipitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "洪水", "Back": "flood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公然", "Back": "open (e.g. secret);public;official", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抗争", "Back": "dispute;resistance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "構想", "Back": "plan;plot;idea;conception", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拘束", "Back": "restriction;restraint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "後退", "Back": "retreat;backspace (BS)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "光沢", "Back": "brilliance;polish;lustre;glossy finish (of photographs)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公団", "Back": "public corporation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好調", "Back": "favourable;promising;satisfactory;in good shape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "口頭", "Back": "oral", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "講読", "Back": "reading;translation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "購読", "Back": "subscription (e.g. magazine)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "購入", "Back": "purchase;buy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公認", "Back": "official recognition;authorization;licence;accreditation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "光熱費", "Back": "cost of fuel and light", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "荒廃", "Back": "ruin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "購買", "Back": "purchase;buy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好評", "Back": "popularity;favorable reputation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交付", "Back": "delivering;furnishing (with copies)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "降伏", "Back": "capitulation;surrender;submission", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "興奮", "Back": "excitement;stimulation;agitation;arousal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公募", "Back": "public appeal;public contribution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巧妙", "Back": "ingenious;skillful;clever;deft", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公用", "Back": "government business;public use;public expense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小売", "Back": "retail", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "効率", "Back": "efficiency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公立", "Back": "public (institution)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小柄", "Back": "short (build)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小切手", "Back": "cheque;check", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国産", "Back": "domestic products", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国定", "Back": "state-sponsored;national", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国土", "Back": "realm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "告白", "Back": "confession;acknowledgement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国防", "Back": "national defence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国有", "Back": "national ownership", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国連", "Back": "U.N.;United Nations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漕ぐ", "Back": "to row;to scull;to pedal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "焦げ茶", "Back": "black tea", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "個々", "Back": "individual;one by one", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "箇箇", "Back": "individual;separate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心地", "Back": "feeling;sensation;mood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心得", "Back": "knowledge;information", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心掛け", "Back": "readiness;intention;aim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心掛ける", "Back": "to bear in mind;to aim to do", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "志", "Back": "will;intention;motive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "志す", "Back": "to plan;to intend;to aspire to;to set aims (sights on)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心強い", "Back": "heartening;reassuring", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心細い", "Back": "helpless;forlorn;hopeless;unpromising;lonely;discouraging;disheartening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "試み", "Back": "trial;experiment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "試みる", "Back": "to try;to test", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "快い", "Back": "pleasant;agreeable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凝らす", "Back": "to freeze;to congeal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凝る", "Back": "to congeal;to freeze", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拵える", "Back": "to make;to manufacture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "孤児", "Back": "orphan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拗れる", "Back": "to get complicated;to grow worse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "故人", "Back": "the deceased;old friend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "梢", "Back": "treetop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "個性", "Back": "individuality;personality;idiosyncrasy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戸籍", "Back": "census;family register", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小銭", "Back": "coins;small change", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "固体", "Back": "solid (body)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "堪える", "Back": "to bear;to stand;to endure;to put up with;to support;to withstand;to resist;to brave;to be fit for;t", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "答え", "Back": "answer;response", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火燵", "Back": "table with heater;(orig) charcoal brazier in a floor well", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "古代", "Back": "ancient times", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こだわる", "Back": "to fuss over;to be particular about;to be concerned about", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誇張", "Back": "exaggeration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滑稽", "Back": "funny;humorous;comical;laughable;ridiculous;joking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国交", "Back": "diplomatic relations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "骨董品", "Back": "curio", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "骨", "Back": "knack;skill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "固定", "Back": "fixation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事柄", "Back": "matter;thing;affair;circumstance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悉く", "Back": "altogether;entirely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言伝", "Back": "declaration;hearsay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殊に", "Back": "especially;above all", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事によると", "Back": "depending on the circumstances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "孤独", "Back": "isolation;loneliness;solitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粉々", "Back": "in very small pieces", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "此の", "Back": "this", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "この間", "Back": "the other day;lately;recently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "この頃", "Back": "recently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好ましい", "Back": "nice;likeable;desirable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "個別", "Back": "particular case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "零す", "Back": "to spill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "零れる", "Back": "to overflow;to spill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "細やか", "Back": "friendly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混む", "Back": "to be crowded", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "込める", "Back": "to include;to put into", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "篭る", "Back": "to seclude oneself;to be confined in;to be implied;to be stuffy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "固有", "Back": "characteristic;tradition;peculiar;inherent;eigen-", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雇用", "Back": "employment (long term);hire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暦", "Back": "calendar;almanac", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "孤立", "Back": "isolation;helplessness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "懲りる", "Back": "to learn by experience;to be disgusted with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "此れ", "Back": "this", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "此れ等", "Back": "these", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "魂", "Back": "soul;spirit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "根気", "Back": "patience;perseverance;energy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "根拠", "Back": "basis;foundation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混血", "Back": "mixed race;mixed parentage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "昆虫", "Back": "insect;bug", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "根底", "Back": "root;basis;foundation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混同", "Back": "confusion;mixing;merger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "今日は", "Back": "hello;good day (daytime greeting&nbsp;&nbsp;id)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "今晩は", "Back": "good evening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "根本", "Back": "origin;source;foundation;root;base;principle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御", "Back": "go-;honourable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "語彙", "Back": "vocabulary;glossary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濠", "Back": "moat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "業", "Back": "Buddhist karma;actions committed in a former life", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "号", "Back": "number;issue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合意", "Back": "agreement;consent;mutual understanding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合議", "Back": "consultation;conference", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強気", "Back": "great;grand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合成", "Back": "synthesis;composition;synthetic;composite;mixed;combined;compound", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "護衛", "Back": "guard;convoy;escort", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "語句", "Back": "words;phrases", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "極楽", "Back": "paradise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ご苦労様", "Back": "Thank you very much for your....", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "語源", "Back": "word root;word derivation;etymology", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誤差", "Back": "error", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ご座います", "Back": "to be (polite);to exist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ご馳走", "Back": "feast;treating (someone)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ご馳走さま", "Back": "feast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "毎", "Back": "each respectively", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "碁盤", "Back": "Go board", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ご無沙汰", "Back": "not writing or contacting for a while", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誤魔化す", "Back": "to deceive;to falsify;to misrepresent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御免ください", "Back": "May I come in?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御免なさい", "Back": "I beg your pardon;excuse me", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御覧なさい", "Back": "(please) look;(please) try to do", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "佐", "Back": "help", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再", "Back": "re-;again;repeated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差異", "Back": "difference;disparity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歳", "Back": "#NAME?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再会", "Back": "another meeting;meeting again;reunion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "災害", "Back": "calamity;disaster;misfortune", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "細菌", "Back": "bacillus;bacterium;germ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "細工", "Back": "work;craftsmanship;tactics;trick", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "採掘", "Back": "mining", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "採決", "Back": "vote;roll call", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再建", "Back": "rebuilding;reconstruction;rehabilitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再現", "Back": "reappearance;reproduction;return;revival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "採算", "Back": "profit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "採集", "Back": "collecting;gathering", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再生", "Back": "playback;regeneration;resuscitation;return to life;rebirth;reincarnation;narrow escape;reclamation;r", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "最善", "Back": "the very best", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "採択", "Back": "adoption;selection;choice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再発", "Back": "return;relapse;reoccurrence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "栽培", "Back": "cultivation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "細胞", "Back": "cell (biology)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "採用", "Back": "use;adopt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遮る", "Back": "to interrupt;to intercept;to obstruct", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "囀る", "Back": "to sing;to chirp;to twitter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冴える", "Back": "to be clear;to be serene;to be cold;to be skillful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "竿", "Back": "rod;pole (e.g. for drying laundry)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "栄える", "Back": "to prosper;to flourish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "杯", "Back": "wine cups", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逆立ち", "Back": "handstand;headstand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逆上る", "Back": "to go back;to go upstream;to make retroactive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盛る", "Back": "to prosper;to flourish;to copulate (animals)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差額", "Back": "balance;difference;margin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下がる", "Back": "to hang down;to abate;to retire;to fall;to step back", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一昨昨日", "Back": "two days before yesterday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先に", "Back": "before;earlier than;ahead;beyond;away;previously;recently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詐欺", "Back": "fraud;swindle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作", "Back": "a work;a harvest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "策", "Back": "plan;policy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "柵", "Back": "fence;paling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "削減", "Back": "cut;reduction;curtailment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "錯誤", "Back": "mistake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作戦", "Back": "military or naval operations;tactics;strategy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作物", "Back": "literary work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "叫び", "Back": "shout;scream;outcry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裂ける", "Back": "to split;to tear;to burst", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捧げる", "Back": "to lift up;to give;to offer;to consecrate;to devote;to sacrifice;to dedicate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差し掛かる", "Back": "to come near to;to approach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指図", "Back": "instruction;mandate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差し出す", "Back": "to present;to submit;to tender;to hold out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差し支える", "Back": "to interfere;to hinder;to become impeded", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差し引く", "Back": "to deduct", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "些事", "Back": "something small or petty;trifle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "授ける", "Back": "to grant;to award;to teach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嘸", "Back": "I am sure;certainly;no doubt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定まる", "Back": "to become settled;to be fixed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定める", "Back": "to decide;to establish;to determine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "錯覚", "Back": "optical illusion;hallucination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "早急", "Back": "urgent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "察する", "Back": "to guess;to sense;to presume;to judge;to sympathize with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "さっと", "Back": "quickly;suddenly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冊", "Back": "counter for books", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殺人", "Back": "murder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偖", "Back": "well;now;then", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悟る", "Back": "to attain enlightenment;to perceive;to understand;to discern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真実", "Back": "truth;reality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裁く", "Back": "to judge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "錆び", "Back": "rust (colour)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "左程", "Back": "(not) very;(not) much", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "様", "Back": "Mr. or Mrs.;manner;kind;appearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "三味線", "Back": "three-stringed Japanese guitar;shamisen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "侍", "Back": "Samurai;warrior", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "然も", "Back": "with gusto;with satisfaction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作用", "Back": "action;operation;effect;function", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "左様なら", "Back": "good-bye", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拐う", "Back": "to carry off;to run away with;to kidnap;to abduct", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "爽やか", "Back": "fresh;refreshing;invigorating;clear;fluent;eloquent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "障る", "Back": "to hinder;to interfere with;to affect;to do one harm;to be harmful to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酸", "Back": "acid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "さん", "Back": "Mr or Mrs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酸化", "Back": "oxidation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "山岳", "Back": "mountains", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "産休", "Back": "maternity leave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "桟橋", "Back": "wharf;bridge;jetty;pier", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "参議院", "Back": "House of Councillors", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "産後", "Back": "postpartum;after childbirth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "産出", "Back": "yield;produce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "参照", "Back": "reference;consultation;consultation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "参上", "Back": "calling on;visiting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賛成", "Back": "approval;agreement;support;favour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賛美", "Back": "praise;adoration;glorification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "産婦人科", "Back": "maternity and gynecology department", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "産物", "Back": "product;result;fruit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "山腹", "Back": "hillside;mountainside", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "山脈", "Back": "mountain range", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "財", "Back": "fortune;riches", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "財源", "Back": "source of funds;resources;finances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "在庫", "Back": "stockpile;stock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "財政", "Back": "economy;financial affairs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "座談会", "Back": "symposium;round-table discussion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雑貨", "Back": "miscellaneous goods;general goods;sundries", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雑", "Back": "rough;crude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雑談", "Back": "chatting;idle talk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雑木", "Back": "various kinds of small trees;assorted trees", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "座標", "Back": "coordinate(s)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "残金", "Back": "remaining money", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "残酷", "Back": "cruelty;harshness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "残高", "Back": "(bank) balance;remainder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "死", "Back": "death;decease", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "し", "Back": "10^24 (kanji is JIS X 0212 kuten 4906);septillion (American);quadrillion (British)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "次", "Back": "order;sequence;times;next;below", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕上がり", "Back": "finish;end;completion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕上げ", "Back": "end;finishing touches;being finished", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕上げる", "Back": "to finish up;to complete", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明々後日", "Back": "two days after tomorrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飼育", "Back": "breeding;raising;rearing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強いて", "Back": "by force", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強いる", "Back": "to force;to compel;to coerce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕入れる", "Back": "to lay in stock;to replenish stock;to procure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しいんと", "Back": "silent (as the grave);(deathly) quiet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歯科", "Back": "dentistry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "資格", "Back": "qualifications;requirements;capabilities", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "視覚", "Back": "sense of sight;vision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕掛け", "Back": "device;trick;mechanism;gadget;(small) scale;half finished;commencement;set up;challenge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕掛ける", "Back": "to commence;to lay (mines);to set (traps);to wage (war);to challenge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "然し", "Back": "however;but", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "然しながら", "Back": "nevertheless;however", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "而も", "Back": "moreover;furthermore;nevertheless;and yet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "市街", "Back": "urban areas;the streets;town;city", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指揮", "Back": "command;direction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "色彩", "Back": "colour;hue;tints", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "式場", "Back": "ceremonial hall;place of ceremony (e.g. marriage)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "為来り", "Back": "customs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頻りに", "Back": "frequently;repeatedly;incessantly;eagerly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕切る", "Back": "to partition;to divide;to mark off;to settle accounts;to toe the mark", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "資金", "Back": "funds;capital", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "施行", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;execution;enforcing;carrying out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しくじる", "Back": "to fail;to fall through;to blunder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕組み", "Back": "devising;plan;plot;contrivance;construction;arrangement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "死刑", "Back": "death penalty;capital punishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "湿気る", "Back": "to be damp;to be moist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思考", "Back": "thought", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "志向", "Back": "intention;aim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嗜好", "Back": "taste;liking;preference", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "視察", "Back": "inspection;observation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "資産", "Back": "property;fortune;means;assets", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刺繍", "Back": "embroidery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支持", "Back": "support;maintenance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指示", "Back": "indication;instruction;directions", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雫", "Back": "drop (of water)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沈める", "Back": "to sink;to submerge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "施設", "Back": "institution;establishment;facility;(army) engineer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "子息", "Back": "son", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慕う", "Back": "to yearn for;to miss;to adore;to love dearly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "従って", "Back": "therefore;consequently;in accordance with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下心", "Back": "secret intention;motive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "親しむ", "Back": "to be intimate with;to befriend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下調べ", "Back": "preliminary investigation;preparation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下地", "Back": "groundwork;foundation;inclination;aptitude;elementary knowledge of;grounding in;prearrangement;spade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "認める", "Back": "to write up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕立てる", "Back": "to tailor;to make;to prepare;to train;to send (a messenger)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下取り", "Back": "trade in;part exchange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下火", "Back": "burning low;waning;declining", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "失格", "Back": "disqualification;elimination;incapacity (legal)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確り", "Back": "firmly;tightly;reliable;level-headed;steady", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "質素", "Back": "simplicity;modesty;frugality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "失調", "Back": "lack of harmony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嫉妬", "Back": "jealousy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尻尾", "Back": "tail (animal)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "室", "Back": "room", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "質疑", "Back": "question", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "躾", "Back": "home discipline;training;upbringing;breeding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕付ける", "Back": "to be used to a job;to begin to do;to baste;to tack;to plant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指摘", "Back": "pointing out;identification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "視点", "Back": "opinion;point of view;visual point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "萎びる", "Back": "to wilt;to fade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嫋か", "Back": "supple;flexible;elastic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "屎尿", "Back": "excreta;raw sewage;human waste;night soil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凌ぐ", "Back": "to outdo;to surpass;to endure;to keep out (rain);to stave off;to tide over;to pull through;to defy;t", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "始発", "Back": "first train", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "芝", "Back": "lawn;sod;turf", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "屡", "Back": "often;again and again;frequently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暫く", "Back": "little while", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "痺れる", "Back": "to become numb;to go to sleep (i.e.&nbsp;&nbsp;a limb)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "渋い", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;tasteful (clothing);cool;an aura of refined masculinity; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;astringent;sullen;bitter (taste); 3", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "私物", "Back": "private property;personal effects", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しぶとい", "Back": "tenacious;stubborn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "司法", "Back": "administration of justice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脂肪", "Back": "fat;grease;blubber", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "志望", "Back": "wish;desire;ambition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "萎む", "Back": "to wither;to fade (away);to shrivel;to wilt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕舞", "Back": "end;termination;informal (Noh play)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕舞う", "Back": "to finish;to close;to do something completely;to put away;to put an end to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しまった", "Back": "Damn it!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "始末", "Back": "management;dealing;settlement;cleaning up afterwards", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "泌み泌み", "Back": "keenly;deeply;heartily", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "染みる", "Back": "to pierce;to permeate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "使命", "Back": "mission;errand;message", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "締め切り", "Back": "closing;cut-off;end;deadline;Closed;No Entrance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "僕", "Back": "manservant;servant (of God)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "社交", "Back": "social life;social intercourse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "謝絶", "Back": "refusal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "社宅", "Back": "company owned house", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吃逆", "Back": "hiccough;hiccup", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "喋る", "Back": "to talk;to chat;to chatter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "斜面", "Back": "slope;slanting surface;bevel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "洒落", "Back": "frank;open-hearted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "洒落る", "Back": "to joke;to play on words;to dress stylishly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "視野", "Back": "field of vision;outlook", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "種", "Back": "kind;variety;species", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衆", "Back": "masses;great number;the people", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "周", "Back": "circuit;lap;circumference;vicinity;Chou (dynasty)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "収益", "Back": "earnings;proceeds;returns", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "修学", "Back": "learning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "周期", "Back": "cycle;period", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衆議院", "Back": "Lower House;House of Representatives", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "就業", "Back": "employment;starting work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "修行", "Back": "pursuit of knowledge;studying;learning;training;ascetic practice;discipline", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "集計", "Back": "totalization;aggregate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "襲撃", "Back": "attack;charge;raid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "収支", "Back": "income and expenditure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "終始", "Back": "beginning and end;from beginning to end;doing a thing from beginning to end", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "修士", "Back": "Masters degree program", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "収集", "Back": "gathering up;collection;accumulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "修飾", "Back": "ornamentation;embellishment;decoration;adornment;polish up (writing);modification (gram)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "終日", "Back": "all day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "執着", "Back": "attachment;adhesion;tenacity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "収容", "Back": "accommodation;reception;seating;housing;custody;admission;entering (in a dictionary)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "修了", "Back": "completion (of a course)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "守衛", "Back": "security guard;doorkeeper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主演", "Back": "starring;playing the leading part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主観", "Back": "subjectivity;subject;ego", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祝賀", "Back": "celebration;congratulations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宿命", "Back": "fate;destiny;predestination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主権", "Back": "sovereignty;supremacy;dominion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手芸", "Back": "handicrafts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主催", "Back": "organization;sponsorship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取材", "Back": "choice of subject;collecting data", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "趣旨", "Back": "object;meaning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主食", "Back": "staple food", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主人公", "Back": "protagonist;main character;hero(ine) (of a story);head of household", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主体", "Back": "subject;main constituent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主題", "Back": "subject;theme;motif", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出血", "Back": "bleeding;haemorrhage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出産", "Back": "(child)birth;delivery;production (of goods)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出社", "Back": "arrival (in a country&nbsp;&nbsp;at work&nbsp;&nbsp;etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出生", "Back": "birth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出世", "Back": "promotion;successful career;eminence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出費", "Back": "expenses;disbursements", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出品", "Back": "exhibit;display", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出演", "Back": "performance;stage appearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出題", "Back": "proposing a question", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出動", "Back": "sailing;marching;going out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主導", "Back": "main leadership", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主任", "Back": "person in charge;responsible official", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "首脳", "Back": "head;brains", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "守備", "Back": "defense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手法", "Back": "technique", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "私有", "Back": "private ownership", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "諸", "Back": "various;many;several", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "背負う", "Back": "to be burdened with;to carry on back or shoulder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "象", "Back": "phenomenon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "症", "Back": "illness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傷", "Back": "wound;injury;hurt;cut;gash;bruise;scratch;scar;weak point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "商", "Back": "quotient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消去", "Back": "elimination;erasing;dying out;melting away", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衝撃", "Back": "shock;crash;impact;ballistic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "証言", "Back": "evidence;testimony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "証拠", "Back": "evidence;proof", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消耗", "Back": "exhaustion;consumption", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "照合", "Back": "collation;comparison", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詳細", "Back": "detail;particulars", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "昇進", "Back": "promotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "少数", "Back": "minority;few", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "称する", "Back": "to pretend;to take the name of;to feign;to purport", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消息", "Back": "news;letter;circumstances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "承諾", "Back": "consent;acquiescence;agreement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "象徴", "Back": "symbol", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小児科", "Back": "pediatrics", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "証人", "Back": "witness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "照明", "Back": "illumination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勝利", "Back": "victory;triumph;conquest;success;win", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奨励", "Back": "encouragement;promotion;message;address", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "職員", "Back": "staff member;personnel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "植民地", "Back": "colony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "職務", "Back": "professional duties", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "諸君", "Back": "Gentlemen!;Ladies!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所在", "Back": "whereabouts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所々", "Back": "here and there;some parts (of something)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所持", "Back": "possession;owning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所属", "Back": "attached to;belong to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "処置", "Back": "treatment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しょっちゅう", "Back": "always;constantly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所定", "Back": "fixed;prescribed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所得", "Back": "income;earnings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "初版", "Back": "first edition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "処罰", "Back": "punishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書評", "Back": "book review", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "処分", "Back": "disposal;dealing;punishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "庶民", "Back": "masses;common people", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "庶務", "Back": "general affairs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "私用", "Back": "personal use;private business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕様", "Back": "way;method;resource;remedy;(technical) specification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "使用人", "Back": "employee;servant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調べ", "Back": "preparation;investigation;inspection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知り合い", "Back": "acquaintance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退く", "Back": "to retreat;to recede;to withdraw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退ける", "Back": "to repel;to drive away", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記す", "Back": "to note;to write down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指令", "Back": "orders;instructions;directive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代", "Back": "price;materials;substitution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "皺", "Back": "wrinkles;creases", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新", "Back": "new", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進化", "Back": "evolution;progress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殿", "Back": "rear;rear unit guard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "審議", "Back": "deliberation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進行", "Back": "advance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新興", "Back": "rising;developing;emergent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "振興", "Back": "promotion;encouragement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申告", "Back": "report;statement;filing a return;notification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新婚", "Back": "newly-wed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "審査", "Back": "judging;inspection;examination;investigation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紳士", "Back": "gentleman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進出", "Back": "advance;step forward", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "信者", "Back": "believer;adherent;devotee;Christian", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真珠", "Back": "pearl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心中", "Back": "double suicide;lovers suicide", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心情", "Back": "mentality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新人", "Back": "new face;newcomer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "神聖", "Back": "holiness;sacredness;dignity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "親善", "Back": "friendship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真相", "Back": "truth;real situation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新築", "Back": "new building;new construction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進呈", "Back": "presentation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進展", "Back": "progress;development", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "神殿", "Back": "temple;sacred place", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進度", "Back": "progress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "振動", "Back": "oscillation;vibration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新入生", "Back": "freshman;first-year student", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "信任", "Back": "trust;confidence;credence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "審判", "Back": "refereeing;trial;judgement;umpire;referee", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "神秘", "Back": "mystery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辛抱", "Back": "patience;endurance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真理", "Back": "truth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "侵略", "Back": "aggression;invasion;raid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "診療", "Back": "medical examination and treatment;diagnosis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進路", "Back": "course;route", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自覚", "Back": "self-conscious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地方", "Back": "area;locality;district;region;the coast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自我", "Back": "self;the ego", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "磁気", "Back": "magnetism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "磁器", "Back": "porcelain;china", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事業", "Back": "project;enterprise;business;industry;operations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地形", "Back": "terrain;geographical features;topography", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軸", "Back": "axis;stem;shaft;axle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自己", "Back": "self;oneself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事項", "Back": "matter;item;facts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "時刻表", "Back": "table;diagram;chart;timetable;schedule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地獄", "Back": "hell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "時差", "Back": "time difference", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自在", "Back": "freely;at will", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自主", "Back": "independence;autonomy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自首", "Back": "surrender;give oneself up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辞職", "Back": "resignation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自信", "Back": "self-confidence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事前", "Back": "prior;beforehand;in advance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自尊心", "Back": "self-respect;conceit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "持続", "Back": "continuation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "字体", "Back": "type;font;lettering", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辞退", "Back": "refusal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "じっくり", "Back": "deliberately;carefully", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実質", "Back": "substance;essence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実践", "Back": "practice;put into practice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実態", "Back": "truth;fact", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実費", "Back": "actual expense;cost price", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "十分", "Back": "10 minutes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実", "Back": "truth;reality;sincerity;fidelity;kindness;faith;substance;essence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実業家", "Back": "industrialist;businessman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実情", "Back": "real condition;actual circumstances;actual state of affairs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自転", "Back": "rotation;spin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自動詞", "Back": "intransitive verb (no direct obj)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地主", "Back": "landlord", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "耳鼻科", "Back": "otolaryngology", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地元", "Back": "local", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弱", "Back": "weakness;the weak;little less then", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "若干", "Back": "some;few;number of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "砂利", "Back": "gravel;ballast;pebbles", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "じゃん拳", "Back": "rock-scissors-paper game", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "住", "Back": "dwelling;living", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "従業員", "Back": "employee;worker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "従事", "Back": "engaging;pursuing;following", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "充実", "Back": "fullness;completion;perfection;substantiality;enrichment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "十字路", "Back": "crossroads", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絨毯", "Back": "carpet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "柔軟", "Back": "flexible;lithe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重複", "Back": "duplication;repetition;overlapping;redundancy;restoration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重宝", "Back": "priceless treasure;convenience;usefulness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "従来", "Back": "up to now;so far;traditional", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塾", "Back": "coaching school;lessons", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "樹木", "Back": "trees and shrubs;arbour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "樹立", "Back": "establish;create", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "準急", "Back": "local express (train&nbsp;&nbsp;slower than an express)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "準じる", "Back": "to follow;to conform;to apply to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "準ずる", "Back": "to apply correspondingly;to correspond to;to be proportionate to;to conform to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助", "Back": "help;rescue;assistant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "情", "Back": "feelings;emotion;passion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "畳", "Back": "#NAME?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尉", "Back": "jailer;old man;rank;company officer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嬢", "Back": "young woman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "状", "Back": "shape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上位", "Back": "superior (rank not class);higher order (e.g. byte);host computer (of connected device)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上演", "Back": "performance (e.g. music)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "城下", "Back": "land near the castle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乗客", "Back": "passenger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上空", "Back": "sky;the skies;high-altitude sky;upper air", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上司", "Back": "superior authorities;boss", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "情緒", "Back": "emotion;feeling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上昇", "Back": "rising;ascending;climbing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "情勢", "Back": "state of things;condition;situation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "情熱", "Back": "passion;enthusiasm;zeal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丈夫", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;hero;gentleman;warrior;manly person; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;good health;robustness;strong;solid;durable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "譲歩", "Back": "concession;conciliation;compromise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "条約", "Back": "treaty;pact", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上陸", "Back": "landing;disembarkation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蒸留", "Back": "distillation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "除外", "Back": "exception;exclusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助言", "Back": "advice;suggestion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "徐行", "Back": "going slowly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "女史", "Back": "Ms.", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助詞", "Back": "particle;postposition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助動詞", "Back": "auxiliary verb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自立", "Back": "independence;self-reliance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人", "Back": "man;person;people", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人格", "Back": "personality;character;individuality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人材", "Back": "man of talent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "迅速", "Back": "quick;fast;rapid;swift;prompt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人体", "Back": "human body", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人民", "Back": "people;public", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人目", "Back": "glimpse;public gaze", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水気", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;moisture;dampness;vapor; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;dropsy;edema", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水源", "Back": "source of river;fountainhead", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "推進", "Back": "propulsion;driving force", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水洗", "Back": "flushing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吹奏", "Back": "playing wind instruments", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "推測", "Back": "guess;conjecture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水田", "Back": "(water-filled) paddy field", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "推理", "Back": "reasoning;inference;mystery or detective genre (movie&nbsp;&nbsp;novel&nbsp;&nbsp;etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "数詞", "Back": "numeral", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "崇拝", "Back": "worship;adoration;admiration;cult", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "据え付ける", "Back": "to install;to equip;to mount", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "据える", "Back": "to set (table);to lay (foundation);to place (gun);to apply (moxa)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清々しい", "Back": "fresh;refreshing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過ぎ", "Back": "past;after", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "救い", "Back": "help;aid;relief", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掬う", "Back": "to scoop;to ladle out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "少なくとも", "Back": "at least", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直ぐ", "Back": "immediately;soon;easily;right (near);honest;upright", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "健やか", "Back": "vigorous;healthy;sound", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濯ぐ", "Back": "to rinse;to wash out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進み", "Back": "progress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勧め", "Back": "recommendation;advice;encouragement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裾", "Back": "(trouser) cuff;(skirt) hem;cut edge of a hairdo;foot of mountain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "廃れる", "Back": "to go out of use;to become obsolete;to die out;to go out of fashion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酸っぱい", "Back": "sour;acid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素敵", "Back": "lovely;dreamy;beautiful;great;fantastic;superb;cool;capital", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "即ち", "Back": "that is;namely;i.e.", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すばしこい", "Back": "nimble;smart;quick", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素早い", "Back": "fast;quick;prompt;agile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "済ます", "Back": "to finish;to get it over with;to settle;to conclude;to pay back", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "澄ます", "Back": "to clear;to make clear;to be unruffled;to look unconcerned;to look demure;look prim;put on airs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "済まない", "Back": "sorry (phrase)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "済みません", "Back": "sorry;excuse me", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天皇", "Back": "Emperor of Japan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刷り", "Back": "printing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "剃る", "Back": "to shave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "擦れ違い", "Back": "chance encounter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すれ違う", "Back": "to pass by one another;to disagree;to miss each other", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "擦れる", "Back": "to rub;to chafe;to wear;to become sophisticated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すんなり", "Back": "pass with no objection;slim;slender", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "図々しい", "Back": "impudent;shameless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずばり", "Back": "decisively;decidedly;once and for all;unreservedly;frankly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずぶ濡れ", "Back": "soaked;dripping wet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずらっと", "Back": "in a line;in a row", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずるずる", "Back": "sound or act of dragging;loose;inconclusive but unwanted situation;trailingly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずれ", "Back": "gap;slippage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずれる", "Back": "to slide;to slip off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制", "Back": "system;organization;imperial command;laws;regulation;control;government;suppression;restraint;holdin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "製", "Back": "-made;make", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生育", "Back": "growth;development;breeding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成果", "Back": "results;fruits", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正解", "Back": "correct;right;correct interpretation (answer&nbsp;&nbsp;solution)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正規", "Back": "regular;legal;formal;established;legitimate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正義", "Back": "justice;right;righteousness;correct meaning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生計", "Back": "livelihood;living", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "政権", "Back": "administration;political power", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "精巧", "Back": "elaborate;delicate;exquisite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制裁", "Back": "restraint;sanctions;punishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "政策", "Back": "political measures;policy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清算", "Back": "liquidation;settlement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "星座", "Back": "constellation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生死", "Back": "life and death", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "静止", "Back": "stillness;repose;standing still", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "青春", "Back": "youth;springtime of life;adolescent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "聖書", "Back": "Bible;scriptures", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誠実", "Back": "sincere;honest;faithful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成熟", "Back": "maturity;ripeness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清純", "Back": "purity;innocence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正常", "Back": "normalcy;normality;normal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制する", "Back": "to control;to command;to get the better of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "整然", "Back": "orderly;regular;well-organized;trim;accurate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盛装", "Back": "be dressed up;wear rich clothes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盛大", "Back": "grand;prosperous;magnificent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清濁", "Back": "good and evil;purity and impurity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制定", "Back": "enactment;establishment;creation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "静的", "Back": "static", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "製鉄", "Back": "iron manufacture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "晴天", "Back": "fine weather", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正当", "Back": "just;justifiable;right;due;proper;equitable;reasonable;legitimate;lawful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成年", "Back": "majority;adult age", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制服", "Back": "uniform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "征服", "Back": "conquest;subjugation;overcoming", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "製法", "Back": "manufacturing method;recipe;formula", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "精密", "Back": "precise;exact;detailed;minute;close", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "声明", "Back": "declaration;statement;proclamation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "姓名", "Back": "full name", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制約", "Back": "limitation;restriction;condition;constraints", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生理", "Back": "physiology;menses", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勢力", "Back": "influence;power;might;strength;potency;force;energy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "整列", "Back": "stand in a row;form a line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "急かす", "Back": "to hurry;to urge on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伜", "Back": "son;my son", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "責務", "Back": "duty;obligation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世辞", "Back": "flattery;compliment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世帯", "Back": "household", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世代", "Back": "generation;the world;the age", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切開", "Back": "clearing (land);opening up;cutting through", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "接触", "Back": "touch;contact", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "設置", "Back": "establishment;institution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "折衷", "Back": "compromise;cross;blending;eclecticism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "設定", "Back": "establishment;creation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "説得", "Back": "persuasion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "節", "Back": "node;section;occasion;time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切実", "Back": "compelling;serious;severe;acute;earnest;pressing;urgent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "接続詞", "Back": "conjunction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切ない", "Back": "painful;trying;oppressive;suffocating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "設立", "Back": "establishment;foundation;institution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "攻め", "Back": "attack;offence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世論", "Back": "public opinion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仙", "Back": "hermit;wizard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前", "Back": "before", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繊維", "Back": "fibre;fiber;textile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "選挙", "Back": "election", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宣教", "Back": "religious mission", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宣言", "Back": "declaration;proclamation;announcement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先行", "Back": "preceding;going first", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "選考", "Back": "selection;screening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戦災", "Back": "war damage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "専修", "Back": "specialization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戦術", "Back": "tactics", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "潜水", "Back": "diving", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先先月", "Back": "month before last", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先先週", "Back": "week before last", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先代", "Back": "family predecessor;previous age;previous generation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先だって", "Back": "recently;the other day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先着", "Back": "first arrival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先天的", "Back": "a priori;inborn;innate;inherent;congenital;hereditary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戦闘", "Back": "battle;fight;combat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "潜入", "Back": "infiltration;sneaking in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "船舶", "Back": "ship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "専用", "Back": "exclusive use;personal use", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "占領", "Back": "occupation;capture;possession;have a room to oneself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戦力", "Back": "war potential", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "税務署", "Back": "tax office", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "是正", "Back": "correction;revision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絶版", "Back": "out of print", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絶望", "Back": "despair;hopelessness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "是非とも", "Back": "by all means (with sense of not taking no for an answer)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "膳", "Back": "(small) table;tray;meal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "禅", "Back": "Zen (Buddhism)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全快", "Back": "complete recovery of health", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全盛", "Back": "height of prosperity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前提", "Back": "preamble;premise;reason;prerequisite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前途", "Back": "future prospects;outlook;the journey ahead", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全滅", "Back": "annihilation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "善良", "Back": "goodness;excellence;virtue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前例", "Back": "precedent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "僧", "Back": "monk;priest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沿う", "Back": "to run along;to follow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "添う", "Back": "to accompany;to become married;to comply with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "総", "Back": "whole;all;general;gross", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相応", "Back": "suitability;fitness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "総会", "Back": "general meeting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "創刊", "Back": "launching (e.g. newspaper);first issue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "送金", "Back": "remittance;sending money", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "走行", "Back": "running a wheeled vehicle (e.g. car);traveling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "総合", "Back": "synthesis;coordination;putting together;integration;composite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捜査", "Back": "search (esp. in criminal investigations);investigation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捜索", "Back": "search (esp. for someone or something missing);investigation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "然うして", "Back": "and;like that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "装飾", "Back": "ornament", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "操縦", "Back": "management;handling;control;manipulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "創造", "Back": "creation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "壮大", "Back": "magnificent;grand;majestic;splendid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "騒動", "Back": "strife;riot;rebellion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遭難", "Back": "disaster;shipwreck;accident", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相場", "Back": "market price;speculation;estimation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "装備", "Back": "equipment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "創立", "Back": "establishment;founding;organization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "添える", "Back": "to add to;to attach;to append;to accompany;to garnish;to imitate;to annex", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "即座に", "Back": "immediately;right away", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "促進", "Back": "promotion;acceleration;encouragement;facilitation;spurring on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "即する", "Back": "to conform to;to agree with;to be adapted to;to be based on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "束縛", "Back": "restraint;shackles;restriction;confinement;binding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "側面", "Back": "side;flank;sidelight;lateral", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其処", "Back": "that place;there", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其処で", "Back": "so (conj);accordingly;now;then;thereupon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "損なう", "Back": "to harm;to hurt;to injure;to damage;to fail in doing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其処ら", "Back": "everywhere;somewhere;approximately;that area;around there", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素材", "Back": "raw materials;subject matter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "阻止", "Back": "obstruction;check;hindrance;prevention;interdiction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "然して", "Back": "and", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訴訟", "Back": "litigation;lawsuit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "育ち", "Back": "breeding;growth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "措置", "Back": "measure;step", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其方", "Back": "over there;the other", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素っ気ない", "Back": "cold;short;curt;blunt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "率直", "Back": "frankness;candour;openheartedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外方", "Back": "look (or turn) the other way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "備え付ける", "Back": "to provide;to furnish;to equip;to install", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "備わる", "Back": "to be furnished with;to be endowed with;to possess;to be among;to be one of;to be possessed of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "その上", "Back": "in addition;furthermore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "その内", "Back": "eventually;sooner or later;of the previously mentioned", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "その為", "Back": "hence;for that reason", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "その外", "Back": "besides;in addition;the rest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其の儘", "Back": "without change;as it is (i.e. now)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "聳える", "Back": "to rise;to tower;to soar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素朴", "Back": "simplicity;artlessness;naivete", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "染まる", "Back": "to dye", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "背く", "Back": "to run counter to;to go against;to disobey;to infringe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "染める", "Back": "to dye;to colour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逸らす", "Back": "to turn away;to avert", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反り", "Back": "warp;curvature;curve;arch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れ", "Back": "it;that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れから", "Back": "and then;after that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "各々", "Back": "each;every;either;respectively;severally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れで", "Back": "and (conj);thereupon;because of that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れでは", "Back": "in that situation;well then ...", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れでも", "Back": "but (still);and yet;nevertheless;even so;notwithstanding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れ共", "Back": "or;or else", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れに", "Back": "besides;moreover", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れ程", "Back": "to that degree;extent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "其れ故", "Back": "therefore;for that reason;so", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揃い", "Back": "set;suit;uniform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "徐々", "Back": "gradually;steadily;quietly;slowly;soon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "損失", "Back": "loss", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "存続", "Back": "duration;continuance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沿い", "Back": "along", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "像", "Back": "statue;image;figure;picture;portrait", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "増強", "Back": "augment;reinforce;increase", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蔵相", "Back": "Minister of Finance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "増進", "Back": "promoting;increase;advance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぞんざい", "Back": "rude;careless;slovenly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "他意", "Back": "ill will;malice;another intention;secret purpose;ulterior motive;fickleness;double-mindedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退化", "Back": "degeneration;retrogression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対応", "Back": "interaction;correspondence;coping with;dealing with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体格", "Back": "physique;constitution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大概", "Back": "in general;mainly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退学", "Back": "dropping out of school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大金", "Back": "great cost", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "待遇", "Back": "treatment;reception", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対決", "Back": "confrontation;showdown", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体験", "Back": "personal experience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対抗", "Back": "opposition;antagonism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対して", "Back": "for;in regard to;per", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大衆", "Back": "general public", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退職", "Back": "retirement (from office)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対処", "Back": "deal with;cope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退治", "Back": "extermination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "態勢", "Back": "attitude;conditions;preparations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対談", "Back": "talk;dialogue;conversation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対等", "Back": "equivalent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滞納", "Back": "non-payment;default", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対比", "Back": "contrast;comparison", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大部", "Back": "most (e.g. most part);greater;fairly;a good deal;much", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対辺", "Back": "(geometrical) opposite side", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "待望", "Back": "expectant waiting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怠慢", "Back": "negligence;procrastination;carelessness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対面", "Back": "interview;meeting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対立", "Back": "confrontation;opposition;antagonism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体力", "Back": "physical strength", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対話", "Back": "interactive;interaction;conversation;dialogue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "耐える", "Back": "to bear;to endure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絶える", "Back": "to die out;to peter out;to become extinct", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高", "Back": "quantity;amount;volume;number;amount of money", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高まる", "Back": "to rise;to swell;to be promoted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "焚火", "Back": "(open) fire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沢山", "Back": "many;a lot;much", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逞しい", "Back": "burly;strong;sturdy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巧み", "Back": "skill;cleverness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "類", "Back": "a kind", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丈", "Back": "height;stature;length;measure;all (one has)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "足し算", "Back": "addition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "多数決", "Back": "majority rule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助け", "Back": "assistance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "携わる", "Back": "to participate;to take part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漂う", "Back": "to drift about;to float;to hang in air", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "立方", "Back": "dancing (geisha)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "忽ち", "Back": "at once;in a moment;suddenly;all at once", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "立ち寄る", "Back": "to stop by;to drop in for a short visit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "達者", "Back": "skillful;in good health", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "達成", "Back": "achievement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "たった", "Back": "only;merely;but;no more than", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尊い", "Back": "precious;valuable;priceless;noble;exalted;sacred", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貴い", "Back": "precious;valuable;priceless;noble;exalted;sacred", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尊ぶ", "Back": "to value;to prize;to esteem", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絶つ", "Back": "to sever;to cut off;to suppress;to abstain (from)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盾", "Back": "shield;buckler;escutcheon;pretext", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "建前", "Back": "face;official stance;public position or attitude (as opposed to private thoughts)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奉る", "Back": "to offer;to present;to revere;to do respectfully", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "例え", "Back": "example;even if;if;though;although", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仮令", "Back": "example;even if;if;though;although", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "他動詞", "Back": "transitive verb (direct obj)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辿り着く", "Back": "to grope along to;to struggle on to;to arrive somewhere after a struggle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辿る", "Back": "to follow (road);to pursue (course);to follow up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掌", "Back": "the palm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "楽しむ", "Back": "to enjoy oneself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頼み", "Back": "request;favor;reliance;dependence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煙草", "Back": "(pt:) (n) (uk) tobacco (pt: tabaco);cigarettes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "度々", "Back": "often;repeatedly;frequently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "他方", "Back": "another side;different direction;(on) the other hand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "多忙", "Back": "busy;pressure of work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "給う", "Back": "to receive;to grant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偶に", "Back": "occasionally;once in a while", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "堪らない", "Back": "intolerable;unbearable;unendurable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溜まり", "Back": "collected things;gathering place;arrears", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賜る", "Back": "to grant;to bestow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "例", "Back": "instance;example;case;precedent;experience;custom;usage;parallel;illustration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "躊躇う", "Back": "to hesitate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保つ", "Back": "to keep;to preserve;to hold;to retain;to maintain;to support;to sustain;to last;to endure;to keep we", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "容易い", "Back": "easy;simple;light", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "多様", "Back": "diversity;variety", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弛み", "Back": "slack;slackening;dullness;letdown", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弛む", "Back": "to slacken;to loosen;to relax", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誰", "Back": "adjectival suffix for a person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "垂れる", "Back": "to hang;to droop;to drop;to lower;to pull down;to dangle;to sag;to drip;to ooze;to trickle;to leave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歎", "Back": "grief;sigh;lamentation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反", "Back": "roll of cloth (c. 10 yds.);.245 acres;300 tsubo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単一", "Back": "single;simple;sole;individual;unitory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "短歌", "Back": "tanka;31-syllable Japanese poem", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "担架", "Back": "stretcher;litter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "短気", "Back": "quick temper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "探検", "Back": "exploration;expedition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "短縮", "Back": "shortening;abbreviation;reduction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "箪笥", "Back": "chest of drawers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "炭素", "Back": "carbon (C)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "短大", "Back": "junior college", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単調", "Back": "monotony;monotone;dullness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単独", "Back": "sole;independence;single;solo (flight)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "短波", "Back": "short wave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蛋白質", "Back": "protein", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "第", "Back": "ordinal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "第一", "Back": "first;foremost;# 1", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大胆", "Back": "bold;daring;audacious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "台無し", "Back": "mess;spoiled;(come to) nothing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大便", "Back": "feces;excrement;shit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代弁", "Back": "pay by proxy;act for another;speak for another", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "台本", "Back": "libretto;scenario", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代用", "Back": "substitution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打開", "Back": "break in the deadlock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "妥協", "Back": "compromise;giving in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "妥結", "Back": "agreement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打撃", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;blow;shock;strike;damage; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;batting (baseball)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "駄作", "Back": "poor work;rubbish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脱出", "Back": "escape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脱する", "Back": "to escape from;to get out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脱退", "Back": "secession", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だぶだぶ", "Back": "loose;baggy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "騙す", "Back": "to trick;to cheat;to deceive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だらけ", "Back": "implying (negatively) that something is full of&nbsp;&nbsp;e.g. mistakes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怠い", "Back": "sluggish;feel heavy;languid;dull", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "壇", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;platform;podium;rostrum; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;(arch) mandala", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "団結", "Back": "unity;union;combination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "断言", "Back": "declaration;affirmation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "断然", "Back": "firmly;absolutely;definitely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "段々", "Back": "gradually;by degrees", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "旦那", "Back": "master (of house);husband (informal)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "断面", "Back": "cross section", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弾力", "Back": "elasticity;flexibility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "治安", "Back": "public order", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近付く", "Back": "to approach;to get near;to get acquainted with;to get closer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "違える", "Back": "to change", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "契る", "Back": "to pledge;to promise;to swear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "畜産", "Back": "animal husbandry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "畜生", "Back": "beast;brute;damn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蓄積", "Back": "accumulation;accumulate;store", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知性", "Back": "intelligence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乳", "Back": "milk;breast;loop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "父母", "Back": "father and mother;parents", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縮まる", "Back": "to be shortened;to be contracted;to shrink", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "窒息", "Back": "suffocation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "些とも", "Back": "not at all (neg. verb)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "秩序", "Back": "order;regularity;system;method", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知的", "Back": "intellectual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "著", "Back": "counter for suits of clothing;arriving at ..", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着", "Back": "counter for suits of clothing;arriving at ..", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着手", "Back": "embarkation;launch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着色", "Back": "colouring;coloring", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着席", "Back": "sit down;seat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着目", "Back": "attention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着陸", "Back": "landing;alighting;touch down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着工", "Back": "start of (construction) work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "茶の間", "Back": "living room (Japanese style)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "茶の湯", "Back": "tea ceremony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ちやほや", "Back": "pamper;make a fuss of;spoil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "昼間", "Back": "daytime;during the day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宙返り", "Back": "somersault;looping-the-loop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中継", "Back": "relay;hook-up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "忠告", "Back": "advice;warning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中指", "Back": "middle finger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中傷", "Back": "slander;libel;defamation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "忠実", "Back": "fidelity;faithfulness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中枢", "Back": "centre;pivot;mainstay;nucleus;backbone;central figure;pillar;key man", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抽選", "Back": "lottery;raffle;drawing (of lots)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中断", "Back": "interruption;suspension;break", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中腹", "Back": "irritated;offended", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中毒", "Back": "poisoning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仲人", "Back": "go-between;matchmaker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "昼飯", "Back": "lunch;midday meal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中立", "Back": "neutrality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中和", "Back": "neutralize;counteract", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腸", "Back": "guts;bowels;intestines", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蝶", "Back": "butterfly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "超", "Back": "super-;ultra-;hyper-", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "庁", "Back": "government office", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調印", "Back": "signature;sign;sealing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "聴覚", "Back": "the sense of hearing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長官", "Back": "chief;(government) secretary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "聴講", "Back": "lecture attendance;auditing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "徴収", "Back": "collection;levy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "聴診器", "Back": "stethoscope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "挑戦", "Back": "challenge;defiance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長大", "Back": "very long;great length", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調停", "Back": "arbitration;conciliation;mediation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恰度", "Back": "just;right;exactly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長編", "Back": "long (e.g. novel&nbsp;&nbsp;film)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丁目", "Back": "district of a town;city block (of irregular size)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調理", "Back": "cooking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調和", "Back": "harmony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ちょくちょく", "Back": "often;frequently;now and then;occasionally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直面", "Back": "confrontation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "著書", "Back": "literary work;book", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貯蓄", "Back": "savings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直感", "Back": "intuition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一寸", "Back": "(ateji) (adv int) (uk) just a minute;a short time;a while;just a little;somewhat;easily;readily;rath", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "著名", "Back": "well-known;noted;celebrated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ちらっと", "Back": "at a glance;by accident", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塵取り", "Back": "dustpan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "治療", "Back": "medical treatment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賃金", "Back": "wages", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沈殿", "Back": "precipitation;settlement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沈没", "Back": "sinking;foundering", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沈黙", "Back": "silence;reticence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "陳列", "Back": "exhibition;display;show", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追及", "Back": "gaining on;carrying out;solving (crime)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追跡", "Back": "pursuit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "次いで", "Back": "next;secondly;subsequently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追放", "Back": "exile;banishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "費やす", "Back": "to spend;to devote;to waste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "墜落", "Back": "falling;crashing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通", "Back": "connoisseur;counter for letters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "痛感", "Back": "feeling keenly;fully realizing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通常", "Back": "common;general;usually", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "痛切", "Back": "keen;acute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "杖", "Back": "cane", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遣い", "Back": "mission;simple task;doing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "使い道", "Back": "use", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕える", "Back": "to serve;to work for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "司る", "Back": "to rule;to govern;to administer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "束の間", "Back": "moment;brief time;brief;transient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付き", "Back": "attached to;impression;sociality;appearance;furnished with;under;to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付き合う", "Back": "to associate with;to keep company with;to get on with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月並み", "Back": "every month;common", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尽きる", "Back": "to be used up;to be run out;to be exhausted;to be consumed;to come to an end", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "継ぎ目", "Back": "a joint;joining point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吐く", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;to breathe; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;to tell (lies); 3.&nbsp;&nbsp;to vomit;to disgorge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尽くす", "Back": "to exhaust;to run out;to serve (a person);to befriend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作り", "Back": "make-up;sliced raw fish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "造り", "Back": "make up;structure;physique", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "造る", "Back": "to make;to create;to manufacture;to draw up;to write;to compose;to build;to coin;to cultivate;to org", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繕う", "Back": "to mend;to repair;to fix;to patch up;to darn;to tidy up;to adjust;to trim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "接ぐ", "Back": "to join;to piece together;to set (bones);to graft (trees)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "継ぐ", "Back": "to succeed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付け加える", "Back": "to add one thing to another", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "告げる", "Back": "to inform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辻褄", "Back": "coherence;consistency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "途中", "Back": "on the way;en route", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突っ張る", "Back": "to support;to become stiff;to become taut;to thrust (ones opponent);to stick to (ones opinion);to in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "筒", "Back": "pipe;tube", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "銃", "Back": "gun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突く", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;to thrust;to strike;to attack; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;to poke;to nudge;to pick at", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慎む", "Back": "to be careful;to be chaste or discreet;to abstain or refrain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伝言", "Back": "verbal message;rumor;word", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勤まる", "Back": "to be fit for;to be equal to;to function properly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勤め先", "Back": "place of work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "努めて", "Back": "make an effort!;work hard!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "津波", "Back": "tsunami;tidal wave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抓る", "Back": "to pinch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "募る", "Back": "to invite;to solicit help&nbsp;&nbsp;participation&nbsp;&nbsp;etc", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "唾", "Back": "saliva;sputum", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呟く", "Back": "to mutter;to murmur", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瞑る", "Back": "to close the eyes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "壷", "Back": "tsubo jar;pot;vase", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蕾", "Back": "bud;flower bud", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "躓く", "Back": "to stumble;to trip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "摘む", "Back": "to pinch;to hold;to pick up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詰らない", "Back": "insignificant;boring;trifling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詰まり", "Back": "in short;in brief;in other words;that is to say;in the long run;after all;blockade;stuffing;ultimate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "積もり", "Back": "intention;plan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "露", "Back": "dew", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強まる", "Back": "to get strong;to gain strength", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強める", "Back": "to strengthen;to emphasize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連なる", "Back": "to extend;to stretch out;to stand in a row", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貫く", "Back": "to go through", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連ねる", "Back": "to link;to join;to put together", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "釣り", "Back": "fishing;angling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吊り革", "Back": "strap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "釣鐘", "Back": "hanging bell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吊るす", "Back": "to hang", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手当て", "Back": "allowance;compensation;treatment;medical care", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体", "Back": "appearance;air;condition;state;form", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "提供", "Back": "offer;tender;program sponsoring;furnishing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定義", "Back": "definition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "提携", "Back": "cooperation;tie-up;joint business;link-up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体裁", "Back": "decency;style;form;appearance;show;get-up;format", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "梯子", "Back": "ladder;stairs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定食", "Back": "set meal;special (of the day)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "提示", "Back": "presentation;exhibit;suggest;citation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訂正", "Back": "correction;revision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "停滞", "Back": "stagnation;tie-up;congestion;retention;accumulation;falling into arrears", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "邸宅", "Back": "mansion;residence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定年", "Back": "retirement age", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "堤防", "Back": "bank;weir", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手遅れ", "Back": "too late;belated treatment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手数", "Back": "number of moves;trouble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手掛かり", "Back": "contact;trail;scent;on hand;hand hold;clue;key", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手掛ける", "Back": "to handle;to manage;to work with;to rear;to look after;to have experience with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手軽", "Back": "easy;simple;informal;offhand;cheap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "的", "Back": "-like;typical", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "適応", "Back": "adaptation;accommodation;conformity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "適宜", "Back": "suitability", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "適性", "Back": "aptitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手際", "Back": "performance;skill;tact", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手順", "Back": "process;procedure;protocol", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手錠", "Back": "handcuffs;manacles", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手近", "Back": "near;handy;familiar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "てっきり", "Back": "surely;certainly;beyond doubt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉄鋼", "Back": "iron and steel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "徹する", "Back": "to sink in;to penetrate;to devote oneself;to believe in;to go through;to do intently and exclusively", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉄片", "Back": "iron scraps", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手配", "Back": "arrangement;search (by police)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手筈", "Back": "arrangement;plan;programme", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手引き", "Back": "guidance;guide;introduction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手本", "Back": "model;pattern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手回し", "Back": "preparations;arrangements", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手元", "Back": "on hand;at hand;at home", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "照り返す", "Back": "to reflect;to throw back light", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手分け", "Back": "division of labour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "店", "Back": "store;shop;establishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "点火", "Back": "ignition;lighting;set fire to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転回", "Back": "revolution;rotation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転換", "Back": "convert;divert", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転居", "Back": "moving;changing residence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転勤", "Back": "transfer;transmission", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "点検", "Back": "inspection;examination;checking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転校", "Back": "change schools", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天国", "Back": "paradise;heaven;Kingdom of Heaven", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天才", "Back": "genius;prodigy;natural gift", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天災", "Back": "natural calamity;disaster", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "展示", "Back": "exhibition;display", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天井", "Back": "ceiling;ceiling price", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転じる", "Back": "to turn;to shift;to alter;to distract", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "点線", "Back": "dotted line;perforated line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天体", "Back": "heavenly body", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転転", "Back": "rolling about;moving from place to place;being passed around repeatedly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "てんで", "Back": "(not) at all;altogether;entirely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転任", "Back": "change of post", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "展望", "Back": "view;outlook;prospect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転落", "Back": "fall;degradation;slump", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出合う", "Back": "to meet by chance;to come across;to happen to encounter;to hold a rendezvous;to have a date", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出入り口", "Back": "exit and entrance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "でかい", "Back": "huge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出来物", "Back": "able man;tumour;growth;boil;ulcer;abcess;rash;pimple", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出切る", "Back": "to be out of;to have no more at hand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出くわす", "Back": "to happen to meet;to come across", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出鱈目", "Back": "irresponsible utterance;nonsense;nonsensical;random;haphazard;unsystematic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出直し", "Back": "adjustment;touch up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "田園", "Back": "country;rural districts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電源", "Back": "source of electricity;power (button on TV&nbsp;&nbsp;etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伝説", "Back": "tradition;legend;folklore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電線", "Back": "electric line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伝達", "Back": "transmission (e.g. news);communication;delivery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伝来", "Back": "ancestral;hereditary;imported;transmitted;handed down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "と", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;if (conjunction); 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;promoted pawn (shogi) (abbr)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "問い合わせる", "Back": "to enquire;to seek information", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "問屋", "Back": "wholesale store", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "問う", "Back": "to ask;to question;to charge (i.e. with a crime);to accuse;without regard to (neg)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "棟", "Back": "place;section;building", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "等", "Back": "et cetera;etc.;and the like", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "陶器", "Back": "pottery;ceramics", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "等級", "Back": "grade;class", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "討議", "Back": "debate;discussion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "登校", "Back": "attendance (at school)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "統合", "Back": "integration;unification;synthesis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "倒産", "Back": "(corporate) bankruptcy;insolvency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "投資", "Back": "investment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "統治", "Back": "rule;reign;government;governing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "統制", "Back": "regulation;control", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当選", "Back": "being elected;winning the prize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逃走", "Back": "flight;desertion;escape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "統率", "Back": "command;lead;generalship;leadership", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "到達", "Back": "reaching;attaining;arrival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "到底", "Back": "(cannot) possibly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丁々", "Back": "clashing of swords;felling of trees;ringing of an ax", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "投入", "Back": "throw;investment;making (an electrical circuit)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当人", "Back": "the one concerned;the said person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逃亡", "Back": "escape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冬眠", "Back": "hibernation;winter sleep", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "登録", "Back": "registration;register;entry;record", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "討論", "Back": "debate;discussion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遠ざかる", "Back": "to go far off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遠回り", "Back": "detour;roundabout way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通りかかる", "Back": "to happen to pass by", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兎角", "Back": "anyhow;anyway;somehow or other;generally speaking;in any case;this and that;many;be apt to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "咎める", "Back": "to blame;to find fault;to take someone to task;to aggravate (an injury)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "時折", "Back": "sometimes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "跡切れる", "Back": "to pause;to be interrupted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "説く", "Back": "to explain;to advocate;to preach;to persuade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特技", "Back": "special skill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特産", "Back": "specialty;special product", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特集", "Back": "feature (e.g. newspaper);special edition;report", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "得点", "Back": "score;points made;marks obtained;runs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特派", "Back": "send specially;special envoy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特有", "Back": "characteristic (of);peculiar (to)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "研ぐ", "Back": "to sharpen;to grind;to scour;to hone;to polish;to wash (rice)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刺", "Back": "thorn;splinter;spine;biting words", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遂げる", "Back": "to accomplish;to achieve;to carry out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "床", "Back": "bed;sickbed;alcove;padding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所が", "Back": "however;while;even if", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所で", "Back": "by the way;even if;no matter what", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年頃", "Back": "age;marriageable age;age of puberty;adolescence;for some years", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年寄り", "Back": "old people;the aged", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戸締り", "Back": "closing up;fastening the doors", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "途上", "Back": "en route;half way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "綴じる", "Back": "to bind;to file", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "途絶える", "Back": "to stop;to cease;to come to an end", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特許", "Back": "special permission;patent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "疾っくに", "Back": "long ago;already;a long time ago", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特権", "Back": "privilege;special right", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "咄嗟", "Back": "moment;instant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取っ手", "Back": "handle;grip;knob", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突破", "Back": "breaking through;breakthrough;penetration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突如", "Back": "suddenly;all of a sudden", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "迚も", "Back": "very;awfully;exceedingly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "整える", "Back": "to put in order;to get ready;to arrange;to adjust", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "届け", "Back": "report;notification;registration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滞る", "Back": "to stagnate;to be delayed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "止まる", "Back": "to be limited to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "留める", "Back": "to stop;to cease;to put an end to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "止める", "Back": "to stop;to cease;to put an end to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "唱える", "Back": "to recite;to chant;to call upon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兎に角", "Back": "anyhow;at any rate;anyway;somehow or other;generally speaking;in any case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殿様", "Back": "feudal lord", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幕", "Back": "curtain;bunting;act (in play)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "帳", "Back": "curtain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "扉", "Back": "door;opening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "徒歩", "Back": "walking;going on foot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乏しい", "Back": "meagre;scarce;limited;destitute;hard up;scanty;poor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "富", "Back": "wealth;fortune", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "富む", "Back": "to be rich;to become rich", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兎も角", "Back": "anyhow;anyway;somehow or other;generally speaking;in any case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共稼ぎ", "Back": "working together;(husband and wife) earning a living together", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "灯", "Back": "light", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伴う", "Back": "to accompany;to bring with;to be accompanied by;to be involved in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共働き", "Back": "dual income", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捕らえる", "Back": "to seize;to grasp;to capture;to arrest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取りあえず", "Back": "at once;first of all;for the time being", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り扱い", "Back": "treatment;service;handling;management", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り扱う", "Back": "to treat;to handle;to deal in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鳥居", "Back": "torii (Shinto shrine archway)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り替え", "Back": "swap;exchange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り組む", "Back": "to tackle;to wrestle with;to engage in a bout;to come to grips with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り締まり", "Back": "control;management;supervision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り締まる", "Back": "to manage;to control;to supervise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り調べる", "Back": "to investigate;to examine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り立てる", "Back": "to collect;to extort;to appoint;to promote", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り次ぐ", "Back": "to act as an agent for;to announce (someone);to convey (a message)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り除く", "Back": "to remove;to take away;to set apart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り引き", "Back": "transactions;dealings;business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り巻く", "Back": "to surround;to circle;to enclose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り混ぜる", "Back": "to mix;to put together", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り戻す", "Back": "to take back;to regain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り寄せる", "Back": "to order;to send away for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り分", "Back": "especially;above all", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "副", "Back": "especially;above all", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蕩ける", "Back": "to be enchanted with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "とんだ", "Back": "terrible;awful;serious;preposterous;absolutely not", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "胴", "Back": "trunk;body;frame", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "働", "Back": "work;labor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同", "Back": "the same;the said;ibid.", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同意", "Back": "agreement;consent;same meaning;same opinion;approval", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動員", "Back": "mobilization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同感", "Back": "agreement;same opinion;same feeling;sympathy;concurrence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動機", "Back": "motive;incentive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同級", "Back": "the same grade;same class", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同居", "Back": "living together", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動向", "Back": "trend;tendency;movement;attitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同士", "Back": "fellow;companion;comrade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同志", "Back": "same mind;comrade;kindred soul", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "如何して", "Back": "why?;for what reason;how;in what way;for what purpose;what for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "如何しても", "Back": "by all means;at any cost;no matter what;after all;in the long run;cravingly;at any rate;surely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同情", "Back": "sympathy;compassion;sympathize;pity;feel for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "道場", "Back": "dojo;hall used for martial arts training;mandala", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何卒", "Back": "please;kindly;by all means", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どうぞ宜しく", "Back": "pleased to meet you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同調", "Back": "sympathy;agree with;alignment;tuning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動的", "Back": "dynamic;kinetic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同等", "Back": "equality;equal;same rights;same rank", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "堂々", "Back": "magnificent;grand;impressive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どうにか", "Back": "in some way or other;one way or another", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "導入", "Back": "introduction;bringing in;leading in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同封", "Back": "enclosure (e.g. in a letter)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同盟", "Back": "alliance;union;league", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どうやら", "Back": "it seems like;somehow or other", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動揺", "Back": "disturbance;unrest;shaking;trembling;pitching;rolling;oscillation;agitation;excitement;commotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動力", "Back": "power;motive power;dynamic force", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独裁", "Back": "dictatorship;despotism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "読者", "Back": "reader", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独自", "Back": "original;peculiar;characteristic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独占", "Back": "monopoly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独創", "Back": "originality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何処", "Back": "where;what place", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何処か", "Back": "somewhere;anywhere;in some respects", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土産", "Back": "product of the land", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土台", "Back": "foundation;base;basis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何方", "Back": "which;who", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土手", "Back": "embankment;bank", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怒鳴る", "Back": "to shout;to yell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何の", "Back": "which;what", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土俵", "Back": "arena", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土木", "Back": "public works", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何々", "Back": "which (emphatic)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "度忘れ", "Back": "lapse of memory;forget for a moment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鈍感", "Back": "thickheadedness;stolidity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内閣", "Back": "cabinet;(government) ministry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乃至", "Back": "from...to;between...and;or", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内臓", "Back": "internal organs;intestines;viscera", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内部", "Back": "interior;inside;internal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内乱", "Back": "civil war;insurrection;rebellion;domestic conflict", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内陸", "Back": "inland", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苗", "Back": "rice seedling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尚", "Back": "furthermore;still;yet;more;still more;greater;further;less", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尚更", "Back": "all the more;still less", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中程", "Back": "middle;midway", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流し", "Back": "sink", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長々", "Back": "long;drawn-out;very long", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殴る", "Back": "to strike;to hit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嘆く", "Back": "to sigh;to lament;to grieve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "投げ出す", "Back": "to throw down;to abandon;to sacrifice;to throw out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "和やか", "Back": "mild;calm;gentle;quiet;harmonious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名残", "Back": "remains;traces;memory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "情け", "Back": "sympathy;compassion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "情け深い", "Back": "tender-hearted;compassionate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "為さる", "Back": "to do", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詰る", "Back": "to rebuke;to scold;to tell off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何故", "Back": "why;how", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何故なら", "Back": "because", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名高い", "Back": "famous;celebrated;well-known", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雪崩", "Back": "avalanche", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "懐く", "Back": "to become emotionally attached", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名付ける", "Back": "to name (someone)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何気ない", "Back": "casual;unconcerned", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何しろ", "Back": "at any rate;anyhow;anyway;in any case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何も", "Back": "nothing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何より", "Back": "most;best", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "七日", "Back": "seven days;the seventh day (of the month)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名札", "Back": "name plate;name tag", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生臭い", "Back": "smelling of fish or blood;fish or meat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生温い", "Back": "lukewarm;halfhearted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生身", "Back": "living flesh;flesh and blood;the quick", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉛", "Back": "lead (the metal)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鈍る", "Back": "to become less capable;to grow dull;to become blunt;to weaken", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "並み", "Back": "average;medium;common;ordinary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滑らか", "Back": "smoothness;glassiness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嘗める", "Back": "to lick;to taste;to experience;to make fun of;to make light of;to put down;to treat with contempt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悩ましい", "Back": "seductive;melancholy;languid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悩ます", "Back": "to afflict;to torment;to harass;to molest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悩み", "Back": "trouble(s);worry;distress;anguish;agony;problem", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平均", "Back": "equilibrium;balance;average;mean", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慣らす", "Back": "to accustom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "馴らす", "Back": "to domesticate;to tame", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "並びに", "Back": "and", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成り立つ", "Back": "to conclude;to consist of;to be practical (logical&nbsp;&nbsp;feasible&nbsp;&nbsp;viable);to hold true", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成る丈", "Back": "as much as possible;if possible", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成るべく", "Back": "as much as possible", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慣れ", "Back": "practice;experience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "馴れ馴れしい", "Back": "over-familiar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "難", "Back": "difficulty;hardships;defect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "南", "Back": "south", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なんか", "Back": "things like ...;or something like that .. (often derogatory)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何だか", "Back": "a little;somewhat;somehow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なんだかんだ", "Back": "something or other", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何て", "Back": "how...!;what...!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何と", "Back": "what;how;whatever", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何となく", "Back": "somehow or other;for some reason or another", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何とも", "Back": "nothing (with neg. verb);quite;not a bit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何なり", "Back": "any;anything;whatever", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "荷", "Back": "load;baggage;cargo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "似通う", "Back": "to resemble closely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面皰", "Back": "pimple;acne", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賑わう", "Back": "to prosper;to flourish;to do thriving business;to be crowded with people", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪い", "Back": "hateful;abominable;poor-looking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憎しみ", "Back": "hatred", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肉親", "Back": "blood relationship;blood relative", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肉体", "Back": "the body;the flesh", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逃げ出す", "Back": "to run away;to escape from", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "西日", "Back": "westering sun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滲む", "Back": "to run;to blur;to spread;to blot;to ooze", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日夜", "Back": "day and night;always", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日当", "Back": "daily allowance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "荷造り", "Back": "packing;baling;crating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "担う", "Back": "to carry on shoulder;to bear (burden);to shoulder (gun)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "二人", "Back": "two persons;two people;pair;couple", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "にも拘らず", "Back": "in spite of;nevertheless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入手", "Back": "obtaining;coming to hand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入賞", "Back": "winning a prize or place (in a contest)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入浴", "Back": "bathe;bathing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尿", "Back": "urine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "俄か", "Back": "sudden;abrupt;unexpected;improvised;offhand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "認識", "Back": "recognition;cognizance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "妊娠", "Back": "conception;pregnancy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人情", "Back": "humanity;empathy;kindness;sympathy;human nature;common sense;customs and manners", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "任務", "Back": "duty;function;office;mission;task", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "任命", "Back": "appointment;nomination;ordination;commission;designation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抜かす", "Back": "to omit;to leave out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抜け出す", "Back": "to slip out;to sneak away;to excel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盗み", "Back": "stealing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沼", "Back": "swamp;bog;pond;lake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "音", "Back": "sound;note", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "値打ち", "Back": "value;worth;price;dignity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寝かせる", "Back": "to put to bed;to lay down;to ferment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捻子", "Back": "screw;helix;spiral", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ねじ回し", "Back": "screwdriver", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捻じれる", "Back": "to twist;to wrench;to screw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鼠", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;mouse;rat; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;dark gray;slate color", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "妬む", "Back": "to be jealous;to be envious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強請る", "Back": "to tease;to coax;to solicit;to demand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "熱湯", "Back": "boiling water", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "熱意", "Back": "zeal;enthusiasm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "熱量", "Back": "temperature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粘り", "Back": "stickyness;viscosity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粘る", "Back": "to be sticky;to be adhesive;to persevere;to persist;to stick to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "値引き", "Back": "price reduction;discount", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "根回し", "Back": "making necessary arrangements", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "眠たい", "Back": "sleepy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "練る", "Back": "to knead;to work over;to polish up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "念", "Back": "sense;idea;thought;feeling;desire;concern;attention;care", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年鑑", "Back": "yearbook", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年号", "Back": "name of an era;year number", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "燃焼", "Back": "burning;combustion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年生", "Back": "pupil in .... year;student in .... year", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年長", "Back": "seniority", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "燃料", "Back": "fuel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年輪", "Back": "annual tree ring", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脳", "Back": "brain;memory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農耕", "Back": "farming;agriculture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農場", "Back": "farm (agriculture)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農地", "Back": "agricultural land", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "納入", "Back": "payment;supply", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逃す", "Back": "to let loose;to set free;to let escape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逃れる", "Back": "to escape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軒並み", "Back": "row of houses", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鋸", "Back": "saw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "望ましい", "Back": "desirable;hoped for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "臨む", "Back": "to look out on;to face;to deal with;to attend (function)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乗っ取る", "Back": "to capture;to occupy;to usurp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長閑", "Back": "tranquil;calm;quiet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "罵る", "Back": "to speak ill of;to abuse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "延べ", "Back": "futures;credit (buying);stretching;total", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飲み込む", "Back": "to gulp down;to swallow deeply;to understand;to take in;to catch on to;to learn;to digest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乗り換え", "Back": "transfer (trains&nbsp;&nbsp;buses&nbsp;&nbsp;etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乗り込む", "Back": "to board;to embark on;to get into (a car);to ship (passengers);to man (a ship);to help (someone) int", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刃", "Back": "edge (of a sword)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "派", "Back": "clique;faction;school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "把握", "Back": "grasp;catch;understanding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肺", "Back": "lung", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "廃棄", "Back": "annullment;disposal;abandon;scrap;discarding;repeal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配給", "Back": "distribution (eg. films&nbsp;&nbsp;rice)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配偶者", "Back": "spouse;wife;husband", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拝啓", "Back": "Dear (so and so)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "背景", "Back": "background;scenery;setting;circumstance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "背後", "Back": "back;rear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "灰皿", "Back": "ashtray", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "廃止", "Back": "abolition;repeal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拝借", "Back": "borrowing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "排除", "Back": "exclusion;removal;rejection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "排水", "Back": "drainage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敗戦", "Back": "defeat;losing a war", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配置", "Back": "arrangement (of resources);disposition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配布", "Back": "distribution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配分", "Back": "distribution;allotment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配慮", "Back": "consideration;concern;forethought", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配列", "Back": "arrangement;array (programming)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "映える", "Back": "to shine;to look attractive;to look pretty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破壊", "Back": "destruction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "墓地", "Back": "cemetery;graveyard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捗る", "Back": "to make progress;to move right ahead (with the work);to advance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "果ない", "Back": "fleeting;transient;short-lived;momentary;vain;fickle;miserable;empty;ephemeral", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "諮る", "Back": "to consult with;to confer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "図る", "Back": "to plot;to attempt;to plan;to take in;to deceive;to devise;to design;to refer A to B", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "剥がす", "Back": "to tear off;to peel off;to rip off;to strip off;to skin;to flay;to disrobe;to deprive of;to detach;t", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破棄", "Back": "revocation;annulment;breaking (e.g. treaty)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "泊", "Back": "counter for nights of a stay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "迫害", "Back": "persecution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "薄弱", "Back": "feebleness;weakness;weak", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "白状", "Back": "confession", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "剥ぐ", "Back": "to tear off;to peel off;to rip off;to strip off;to skin;to flay;to disrobe;to deprive of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "派遣", "Back": "dispatch;send", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "励ます", "Back": "to encourage;to cheer;to raise (the voice)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "励む", "Back": "to be zealous;to brace oneself;to endeavour;to strive;to make an effort", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "剥げる", "Back": "to come off;to be worn off;to fade;to discolor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鋏", "Back": "scissors", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "柱", "Back": "pillar;post", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "橋渡し", "Back": "bridge building;mediation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恥", "Back": "shame;embarrassment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弾く", "Back": "to flip;to snap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "始め", "Back": "beginning;start;origin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "始めまして", "Back": "How do you do?;I am glad to meet you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恥じらう", "Back": "to feel shy;to be bashful;to blush", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恥じる", "Back": "to feel ashamed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蓮", "Back": "lotus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "筈", "Back": "it should be so", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弾む", "Back": "to spring;to bound;to bounce;to be stimulated;to be encouraged;to get lively;to treat oneself to;to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破損", "Back": "damage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "機", "Back": "loom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "果たして", "Back": "as was expected;really", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "果たす", "Back": "to accomplish;to fulfill;to carry out;to achieve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裸足", "Back": "barefoot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蜂蜜", "Back": "honey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発掘", "Back": "excavation;exhumation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発生", "Back": "outbreak;spring forth;occurrence;incidence;origin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発足", "Back": "starting;inauguration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "初", "Back": "first;new", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発", "Back": "departure;beginning;counter for gunshots", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発育", "Back": "(physical) growth;development", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発芽", "Back": "burgeoning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発言", "Back": "utterance;speech;proposal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発病", "Back": "attack (disease)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "初耳", "Back": "something heard for the first time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "果て", "Back": "the end;the extremity;the limit(s);the result", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "果てる", "Back": "to end;to be finished;to be exhausted;to die;to perish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "話し合い", "Back": "discussion;conference", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "甚だ", "Back": "very;greatly;exceedingly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "華々しい", "Back": "brilliant;magnificent;spectacular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "花びら", "Back": "(flower) petal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "華やか", "Back": "gay;showy;brilliant;gorgeous;florid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "阻む", "Back": "to keep someone from doing;to stop;to prevent;to check;to hinder;to obstruct;to oppose;to thwart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浜", "Back": "beach;seashore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浜辺", "Back": "beach;foreshore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "填まる", "Back": "to get into;to go into;to fit;to be fit for;to suit;to fall into;to plunge into;to be deceived;to be", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歯磨", "Back": "dentifrice;toothpaste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "填める", "Back": "to get in;to insert;to put on;to make love", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生やす", "Back": "to grow;to cultivate;to wear beard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "早める", "Back": "to hasten;to quicken;to expedite;to precipitate;to accelerate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流行", "Back": "fashionable;fad;in vogue;prevailing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腹立ち", "Back": "anger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原っぱ", "Back": "open field;empty lot;plain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "張り紙", "Back": "paper patch;paper backing;poster", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遥か", "Back": "far;far-away;distant;remote;far off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破裂", "Back": "explosion;rupture;break off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腫れる", "Back": "to swell (from inflammation);to become swollen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "班", "Back": "group;party;section (mil)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "判", "Back": "seal;stamp;monogram signature;judgment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "版", "Back": "edition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繁栄", "Back": "prospering;prosperity;thriving;flourishing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反感", "Back": "antipathy;revolt;animosity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "版画", "Back": "art print", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反響", "Back": "echo;reverberation;repercussion;reaction;influence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "判決", "Back": "judicial decision;judgement;sentence;decree", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反撃", "Back": "counterattack;counteroffensive;counterblow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反射", "Back": "reflection;reverberation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繁殖", "Back": "breed;multiply;increase;propagation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繁盛", "Back": "prosperity;flourishing;thriving", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反する", "Back": "to be inconsistent with;to oppose;to contradict;to transgress;to rebel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "判定", "Back": "judgement;decision;award;verdict", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反応", "Back": "reaction;response", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "半端", "Back": "remnant;fragment;incomplete set;fraction;odd sum;incompleteness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反発", "Back": "repelling;rebound;recover;oppose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反乱", "Back": "insurrection;mutiny;rebellion;revolt;uprising", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "氾濫", "Back": "overflowing;flood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "黴菌", "Back": "bacteria;germ(s)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賠償", "Back": "reparations;indemnity;compensation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "倍率", "Back": "diameter;magnification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "馬鹿馬鹿しい", "Back": "stupid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "馬鹿らしい", "Back": "absurd", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漠然", "Back": "obscure;vague;equivocal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "爆弾", "Back": "bomb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "爆破", "Back": "blast;explosion;blow up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暴露", "Back": "disclosure;exposure;revelation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "化ける", "Back": "to appear in disguise;to take the form of;to change for the worse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "罰", "Back": "(divine) punishment;curse;retribution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伐", "Back": "strike;attack;punish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ばてる", "Back": "to be exhausted;to be worn out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発条", "Back": "spring (e.g. coil&nbsp;&nbsp;leaf)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "散蒔く", "Back": "to disseminate;to scatter;to give money freely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "万", "Back": "many;all", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "万人", "Back": "all people;everybody;10000 people", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "万能", "Back": "all-purpose;almighty;omnipotent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "番目", "Back": "cardinal number suffix", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "非", "Back": "faulty-;non-", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "費", "Back": "cost;expense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "延いては", "Back": "not only...but also;in addition to;consequently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "控室", "Back": "waiting room", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "控える", "Back": "to draw in;to hold back;to make notes;to be temperate in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悲観", "Back": "pessimism;disappointment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "匹", "Back": "head;small animal counter;roll of cloth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引き上げる", "Back": "to withdraw;to leave;to pull out;to retire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "率いる", "Back": "to lead;to spearhead (a group);to command (troops)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引き受ける", "Back": "to undertake;to take up;to take over;to be responsible for;to guarantee;to contract (disease)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引き起こす", "Back": "to cause", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引き下げる", "Back": "to pull down;to lower;to reduce;to withdraw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引きずる", "Back": "to seduce;to drag along;to pull;to prolong;to support", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引き取る", "Back": "to take charge of;to take over;to retire to a private place", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引き分け", "Back": "a draw (in competition);tie game", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "否決", "Back": "rejection;negation;voting down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "非行", "Back": "delinquency;misconduct", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日頃", "Back": "normally;habitually", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "久しい", "Back": "long;long-continued;old (story)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "久し振り", "Back": "after a long time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悲惨", "Back": "misery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "秘書", "Back": "(private) secretary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "比重", "Back": "specific gravity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "密か", "Back": "secret;private;surreptitious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浸す", "Back": "to soak;to dip;to drench", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一向", "Back": "earnestly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "左利き", "Back": "left-handedness;sake drinker;left-hander", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引っ掻く", "Back": "to scratch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引っ掛ける", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;to hang (something) on (something);to throw on (clothes); 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;to hook;to catch;to trap;to ensnar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "必修", "Back": "required (subject)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "匹敵", "Back": "comparing with;match;rival;equal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未", "Back": "eighth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Ram&nbsp;&nbsp;1pm-3pm&nbsp;&nbsp;south-southwest&nbsp;&nbsp;June)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "必然", "Back": "inevitable;necessary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一息", "Back": "puffy;a breath;a pause;an effort", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単", "Back": "one layer;single", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人柄", "Back": "personality;character;personal appearance;gentility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一頃", "Back": "once;some time ago", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人質", "Back": "hostage;prisoner", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一筋", "Back": "a line;earnestly;blindly;straightforwardly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一まず", "Back": "for the present;once;in outline", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一人でに", "Back": "by itself;automatically;naturally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酷い", "Back": "cruel;awful;severe;very bad;serious;terrible;heavy;violent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日取り", "Back": "fixed date;appointed day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雛", "Back": "young bird;chick;doll", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日向", "Back": "sunny place;in the sun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "非難", "Back": "blame;attack;criticism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "避難", "Back": "taking refuge;finding shelter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日の丸", "Back": "the Japanese flag", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火花", "Back": "spark", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日々", "Back": "every day;daily;day after day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悲鳴", "Back": "shriek;scream", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "百科事典", "Back": "encyclopedia", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "百科辞典", "Back": "encyclopedia", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷やかす", "Back": "to banter;to make fun of;to jeer at;to cool;to refrigerate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日焼け", "Back": "sunburn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "票", "Back": "label;ballot;ticket;sign", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "標語", "Back": "motto;slogan;catchword", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ひょっと", "Back": "possibly;accidentally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平たい", "Back": "flat;even;level;simple;plain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "比率", "Back": "ratio;proportion;percentage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肥料", "Back": "manure;fertilizer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "比例", "Back": "proportion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "疲労", "Back": "fatigue;weariness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "広まる", "Back": "to spread;to be propagated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貧困", "Back": "poverty;lack", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "品質", "Back": "quality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "品種", "Back": "brand;kind;description", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貧弱", "Back": "poor;meagre;insubstantial", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頻繁", "Back": "frequency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "美", "Back": "beauty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "微笑", "Back": "smile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "美術", "Back": "art;fine arts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吃驚", "Back": "be surprised;be amazed;be frightened;astonishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "びっしょり", "Back": "wet through;drenched", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "描写", "Back": "depiction;description;portrayal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "びり", "Back": "last on the list;at the bottom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "微量", "Back": "minuscule amount;extremely small quantity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敏感", "Back": "sensibility;susceptibility;sensitive (to);well attuned to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貧乏", "Back": "poverty;destitute;poor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歩", "Back": "pawn (in chess or shogi)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不意", "Back": "sudden;abrupt;unexpected;unforeseen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "封", "Back": "seal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "封鎖", "Back": "blockade;freezing (funds)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "風習", "Back": "custom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "風俗", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;manners;customs; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;sex service;sex industry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "風土", "Back": "natural features;topography;climate;spiritual features", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不可欠", "Back": "indispensable;essential", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "深める", "Back": "to deepen;to heighten;to intensify", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不吉", "Back": "ominous;sinister;bad luck;ill omen;inauspiciousness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不況", "Back": "recession;depression;slump", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "布巾", "Back": "tea-towel;dish cloth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "福", "Back": "good fortune", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "復旧", "Back": "restoration;restitution;rehabilitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "複合", "Back": "composite;complex", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "福祉", "Back": "welfare;well-being", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "覆面", "Back": "mask;veil;disguise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "膨れる", "Back": "to get cross;to get sulky;to swell (out);to expand;to be inflated;to distend;to bulge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不景気", "Back": "business recession;hard times;depression;gloom;sullenness;cheerlessness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "老ける", "Back": "to age", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "布告", "Back": "edict;ordinance;proclamation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "富豪", "Back": "wealthy person;millionaire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "負債", "Back": "debt;liabilities", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相応しい", "Back": "appropriate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不在", "Back": "absence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不山戯る", "Back": "to romp;to gambol;to frolic;to joke;to make fun of;to flirt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "負傷", "Back": "injury;wound", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不審", "Back": "incomplete understanding;doubt;question;distrust;suspicion;strangeness;infidelity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不振", "Back": "dullness;depression;slump;stagnation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不順", "Back": "irregularity;unseasonableness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付属", "Back": "attached;belonging;affiliated;annexed;associated;subordinate;incidental;dependent;auxiliary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "負担", "Back": "burden;charge;responsibility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不調", "Back": "bad condition;not to work out (ie a deal);disagreement;break-off;disorder;slump;out of form", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "復活", "Back": "revival (e.g. musical);restoration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "復興", "Back": "revival;renaissance;reconstruction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沸騰", "Back": "boiling;seething", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仏", "Back": "French", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不図", "Back": "suddenly;casually;accidentally;incidentally;unexpectedly;unintentionally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不当", "Back": "injustice;impropriety;unreasonableness;undeservedness;unfair;invalid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不動産", "Back": "real estate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "赴任", "Back": "(proceeding to) new appointment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腐敗", "Back": "decay;depravity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不評", "Back": "bad reputation;disgrace;unpopularity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不便", "Back": "pity;compassion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不服", "Back": "dissatisfaction;discontent;disapproval;objection;complaint;protest;disagreement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "普遍", "Back": "universality;ubiquity;omnipresence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "踏まえる", "Back": "to be based on;to have origin in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文", "Back": "letter;writings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不明", "Back": "unknown;obscure;indistinct;uncertain;ambiguous;ignorant;lack of wisdom;anonymous;unidentified", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "扶養", "Back": "support;maintenance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "振り", "Back": "pretence;show;appearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "振り出し", "Back": "outset;starting point;drawing or issuing (draft)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不良", "Back": "badness;delinquent;inferiority;failure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浮力", "Back": "buoyancy;floating power", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "震わせる", "Back": "to be shaking;to be trembling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付録", "Back": "appendix;supplement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分", "Back": "minute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憤慨", "Back": "indignation;resentment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紛失", "Back": "losing something", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "噴出", "Back": "spewing;gushing;spouting;eruption;effusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紛争", "Back": "dispute;trouble;strife", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ふんだん", "Back": "plentiful;abundant;lavish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奮闘", "Back": "hard struggle;strenuous effort", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粉末", "Back": "fine powder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "部", "Back": "department;part;category;counter for copies of a newspaper or magazine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "部下", "Back": "subordinate person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぶかぶか", "Back": "too big;baggy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "侮辱", "Back": "insult;contempt;slight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "武装", "Back": "arms;armament;armed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "斑", "Back": "spots;speckles;mottles", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物資", "Back": "goods;materials", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物体", "Back": "body;object", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物議", "Back": "public discussion (criticism)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打付ける", "Back": "to knock;to run into;to nail on;to strike hard;to hit and attack", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仏像", "Back": "Buddhist image (statue)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無難", "Back": "safety;security", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "部門", "Back": "class;group;category;department;field;branch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぶら下げる", "Back": "to hang;to suspend;to dangle;to swing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぶらぶら", "Back": "dangle heavily;swing;sway to and fro;aimlessly;idly;lazily;loiter;loaf;be idle;stroll idly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "武力", "Back": "armed might;military power;the sword;force", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無礼", "Back": "impolite;rude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文化財", "Back": "cultural assets;cultural property", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分業", "Back": "division of labor;specialization;assembly-line production", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文語", "Back": "written language;literary language", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分散", "Back": "dispersion;decentralization;variance (statistics)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分子", "Back": "numerator;molecule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文書", "Back": "document;writing;letter;note;records;archives", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分担", "Back": "apportionment;sharing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分配", "Back": "division;sharing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分母", "Back": "denominator", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分離", "Back": "separation;detachment;segregation;isolation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分裂", "Back": "split;division;break up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兵器", "Back": "arms;weapons;ordinance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "閉口", "Back": "shut mouth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平行", "Back": "(going) side by side;concurrent;abreast;at the same time;occurring together;parallel;parallelism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "閉鎖", "Back": "closing;closure;shutdown;lockout;unsociable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兵士", "Back": "soldier", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平常", "Back": "normal;usual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平方", "Back": "square (e.g. metre);square", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "並列", "Back": "arrangement;parallel;abreast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辟易", "Back": "wince;shrink back;succumbing to;being frightened;disconcerted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "臍", "Back": "navel;belly-button", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "隔たる", "Back": "to be distant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "謙る", "Back": "to deprecate oneself and praise the listener", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経る", "Back": "to pass;to elapse;to experience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "編", "Back": "compilation;editing;completed poem;book;part of book", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偏", "Back": "side;left radical of a character;inclining;inclining toward;biased", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "変革", "Back": "change;reform;revolution;upheaval;(the) Reformation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "返還", "Back": "return;restoration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偏見", "Back": "prejudice;narrow view", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "返済", "Back": "repayment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "変遷", "Back": "change;transition;vicissitudes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "返答", "Back": "reply", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "変動", "Back": "change;fluctuation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弁解", "Back": "explanation;justification;defence;excuse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "便宜", "Back": "convenience;accommodation;advantage;expedience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弁護", "Back": "defense;pleading;advocacy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弁償", "Back": "next word;compensation;reparation;indemnity;reimbursement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弁論", "Back": "discussion;debate;argument", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぺこぺこ", "Back": "fawn;be very hungry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "穂", "Back": "ear (of plant);head (of plant)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保育", "Back": "nursing;nurturing;rearing;lactation;suckling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "倣", "Back": "imitate;follow;emulate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "法案", "Back": "bill (law)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "崩壊", "Back": "collapse;decay (physics);crumbling;breaking down;caving in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "法学", "Back": "law;jurisprudence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放棄", "Back": "abandonment;renunciation;abdication (responsibility&nbsp;&nbsp;right)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宝器", "Back": "treasured article or vessel;outstanding individual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "封建", "Back": "feudalistic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "豊作", "Back": "abundant harvest;bumper crop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方策", "Back": "plan;policy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奉仕", "Back": "attendance;service", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方式", "Back": "form;method;system", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放射", "Back": "radiation;emission", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放射能", "Back": "radioactivity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "報酬", "Back": "remuneration;recompense;reward;toll", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放出", "Back": "release;emit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "報じる", "Back": "to inform;to report", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "報ずる", "Back": "to inform;to report", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放置", "Back": "leave as is;leave to chance;leave alone;neglect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "法廷", "Back": "courtroom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "報道", "Back": "information;report", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "褒美", "Back": "reward;prize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "葬る", "Back": "to bury;to inter;to entomb;to consign to oblivion;to shelve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放り込む", "Back": "to throw into", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放り出す", "Back": "to throw out;to fire;to expel;to give up;to abandon;to neglect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飽和", "Back": "saturation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保温", "Back": "retaining warmth;keeping heat in;heat insulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捕獲", "Back": "capture;seizure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保管", "Back": "charge;custody;safekeeping;deposit;storage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "補給", "Back": "supply;supplying;replenishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "補強", "Back": "compensation;reinforcement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保険", "Back": "insurance;guarantee", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捕鯨", "Back": "whaling;whale fishing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誇る", "Back": "to boast of;to be proud of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "綻びる", "Back": "to come apart at the seams;to begin to open;to smile broadly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保護", "Back": "care;protection;shelter;guardianship;favor;patronage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "干し物", "Back": "dried washing (clothes)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保守", "Back": "conservative;maintaining", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保障", "Back": "guarantee;security;assurance;pledge;warranty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "補償", "Back": "compensation;reparation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "補充", "Back": "supplementation;supplement;replenishment;replenishing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "補助", "Back": "assistance;support;aid;auxiliary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "舗装", "Back": "pavement;road surface", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "補足", "Back": "supplement;complement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発作", "Back": "fit;spasm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ほっと", "Back": "feel relieved", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頬っぺた", "Back": "cheek", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辺り", "Back": "(in the) neighbourhood;vicinity;nearby", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殆ど", "Back": "mostly;almost", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解く", "Back": "to unfasten", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "施す", "Back": "to donate;to give;to conduct;to apply;to perform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保母", "Back": "day care worker in a kindergarten&nbsp;&nbsp;nursery school&nbsp;&nbsp;etc.", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保養", "Back": "health preservation;recuperation;recreation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捕吏", "Back": "constable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捕虜", "Back": "prisoner (of war)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滅びる", "Back": "to be ruined;to go under;to perish;to be destroyed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滅ぼす", "Back": "to destroy;to overthrow;to wreck;to ruin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本格", "Back": "propriety;fundamental rules", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本館", "Back": "main building", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本気", "Back": "seriousness;truth;sanctity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本質", "Back": "essence;true nature;reality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本体", "Back": "substance;real form;object of worship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本音", "Back": "real intention;motive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本の", "Back": "mere;only;just", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本能", "Back": "instinct", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本場", "Back": "home;habitat;center;best place;genuine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本文", "Back": "text (of document);body (of letter)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本名", "Back": "real name", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "卯", "Back": "fourth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Hare&nbsp;&nbsp;5am-7am&nbsp;&nbsp;east&nbsp;&nbsp;February)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "防衛", "Back": "defense;protection;self-defense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "防火", "Back": "fire prevention;fire fighting;fire proof", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "妨害", "Back": "disturbance;obstruction;hindrance;jamming;interference", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紡績", "Back": "spinning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呆然", "Back": "dumbfounded;overcome with surprise;in blank amazement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "膨脹", "Back": "expansion;swelling;increase;growth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冒頭", "Back": "beginning;start;outset", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暴動", "Back": "insurrection;rebellion;revolt;riot;uprising", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暴風", "Back": "storm;windstorm;gale", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暴力", "Back": "violence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "募金", "Back": "fund-raising;collection of funds", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "牧師", "Back": "pastor;minister;clergyman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "母校", "Back": "alma mater", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "没収", "Back": "forfeited", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "坊ちゃん", "Back": "son (of others)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぼつぼつ", "Back": "gradually;here and there;spots;pimples", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "没落", "Back": "ruin;fall;collapse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぼやく", "Back": "to grumble;to complain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぼやける", "Back": "to become dim;to become blurred", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "藍褸", "Back": "rag;scrap;tattered clothes;fault (esp. in a pretense);defect;run-down or junky", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "枚", "Back": "counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "埋蔵", "Back": "buried property;treasure trove", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "舞う", "Back": "to dance;to flutter about;to revolve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真上", "Back": "just above;right overhead", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前売り", "Back": "advance sale;booking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前置き", "Back": "preface;introduction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前もって", "Back": "in advance;beforehand;previously", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "任す", "Back": "to entrust;to leave to a person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "負かす", "Back": "to defeat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賄う", "Back": "to give board to;to provide meals;to pay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "曲がる", "Back": "to turn;to bend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巻", "Back": "volume", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紛らわしい", "Back": "confusing;misleading;equivocal;ambiguous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紛れる", "Back": "to be diverted;to slip into", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "膜", "Back": "membrane;film", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捲る", "Back": "verb suffix to indicate reckless abandon to the activity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真心", "Back": "sincerity;devotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誠", "Back": "truth;faith;fidelity;sincerity;trust;confidence;reliance;devotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真に", "Back": "truly;actually;really", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まごつく", "Back": "to be confused;to be flustered", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正しく", "Back": "surely;no doubt;evidently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正に", "Back": "correctly;surely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勝る", "Back": "to excel;to surpass;to outrival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "増し", "Back": "extra;additional;less objectionable;better;preferable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真下", "Back": "right under;directly below", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "況して", "Back": "still more;still less (with neg. verb);to say nothing of;not to mention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交える", "Back": "to mix;to converse with;to cross (swords)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交わる", "Back": "to cross;to intersect;to associate with;to mingle with;to interest;to join", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "麻酔", "Back": "anaesthesia", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "益々", "Back": "increasingly;more and more", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不味い", "Back": "unappetising;unpleasant (taste&nbsp;&nbsp;appearance&nbsp;&nbsp;situation);ugly;unskilful;awkward;bungling;unwise;untime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "股", "Back": "groin;crotch;thigh", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "跨がる", "Back": "to extend over or into;to straddle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "跨ぐ", "Back": "to straddle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瞬き", "Back": "wink;twinkling (of stars);flicker (of light)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "待ち合わせ", "Back": "appointment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間違う", "Back": "to make a mistake;to be incorrect;to be mistaken", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "待ち遠しい", "Back": "looking forward to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "待ち望む", "Back": "to look anxiously for;to wait eagerly for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区々", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;several;various;divergent;conflicting;different;diverse; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;trivial", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "末期", "Back": "closing years (period&nbsp;&nbsp;days);last stage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真っ二つ", "Back": "in two equal parts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "纏まり", "Back": "conclusion;settlement;consistency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "纏め", "Back": "settlement;conclusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "免れる", "Back": "to escape from;to be rescued from;to avoid;to evade;to avert;to elude;to be exempted;to be relieved", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "招き", "Back": "invitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "麻痺", "Back": "paralysis;palsy;numbness;stupor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "眩しい", "Back": "dazzling;radiant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目蓋", "Back": "eyelid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間々", "Back": "occasionally;frequently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間もなく", "Back": "soon;before long;in a short time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "眉", "Back": "eyebrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鞠", "Back": "ball", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丸ごと", "Back": "in its entirety;whole;wholly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丸っきり", "Back": "completely;perfectly;just as if", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丸で", "Back": "quite;entirely;completely;at all;as if;as though;so to speak", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丸々", "Back": "completely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丸める", "Back": "to make round;to round off;to roll up;to curl up;to seduce;to cajole;to explain away", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "満月", "Back": "full moon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "満場", "Back": "unanimous;whole audience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真ん中", "Back": "middle;centre;mid-way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真ん前", "Back": "right in front;under the nose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真ん丸い", "Back": "perfectly circular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "三", "Back": "(num) three", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見合い", "Back": "formal marriage interview", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見合わせる", "Back": "to exchange glances;to postpone;to suspend operations;to refrain from performing an action", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見落とす", "Back": "to overlook;to fail to notice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未開", "Back": "savage land;backward region;uncivilized", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "味覚", "Back": "taste;palate;sense of taste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見掛ける", "Back": "to (happen to) see;to notice;to catch sight of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "三日月", "Back": "new moon;crescent moon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見方", "Back": "viewpoint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見苦しい", "Back": "unsightly;ugly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見込み", "Back": "hope;prospects;expectation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未婚", "Back": "unmarried", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "惨め", "Back": "miserable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未熟", "Back": "inexperience;unripeness;raw;unskilled;immature;inexperienced", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "微塵", "Back": "particle;atom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見すぼらしい", "Back": "shabby;seedy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見せびらかす", "Back": "to show off;to flaunt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見せ物", "Back": "show;exhibition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "満たす", "Back": "to satisfy;to ingratiate;to fill;to fulfill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乱す", "Back": "to throw out of order;to disarrange;to disturb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乱れる", "Back": "to get confused;to be disordered;to be disturbed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未知", "Back": "not yet known", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "導く", "Back": "to be guided;to be shown", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "身近", "Back": "near oneself;close to one;familiar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "密集", "Back": "crowd;close formation;dense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "密接", "Back": "related;connected;close;intimate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見っともない", "Back": "shameful;indecent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蜜", "Back": "nectar;honey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "密度", "Back": "density", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見積り", "Back": "estimation;quotation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未定", "Back": "not yet fixed;undecided;pending", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見通し", "Back": "perspective;unobstructed view;outlook;forecast;prospect;insight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "源", "Back": "source;origin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "身なり", "Back": "personal appearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "峰", "Back": "peak;ridge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見逃す", "Back": "to miss;to overlook;to leave at large", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見晴らし", "Back": "view", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "身振り", "Back": "gesture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見舞", "Back": "enquiry;expression of sympathy;expression of concern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脈", "Back": "pulse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未練", "Back": "lingering affection;attachment;regret(s);reluctance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見渡す", "Back": "to look out over;to survey (scene);to take an extensive view of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "民主", "Back": "democratic;the head of the nation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "民宿", "Back": "private home providing lodging for travelers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "民族", "Back": "people;race;nation;racial customs;folk customs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "民俗", "Back": "people;race;nation;racial customs;folk customs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "六", "Back": "(num) six", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無意味", "Back": "nonsense;no meaning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "向き", "Back": "direction;situation;exposure;aspect;suitability", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無口", "Back": "reticence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "向け", "Back": "for ~;oriented towards ~", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "婿", "Back": "son-in-law", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無効", "Back": "invalid;no effect;unavailable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無言", "Back": "silence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "毟る", "Back": "to pluck;to pick;to tear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無邪気", "Back": "innocence;simple-mindedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結び", "Back": "ending;conclusion;union", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結び付き", "Back": "connection;relation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結び付く", "Back": "to be connected or related;to join together", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結び付ける", "Back": "to combine;to join;to tie on;to attach with a knot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無線", "Back": "wireless;radio", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無駄遣い", "Back": "waste money on;squander money on;flog a dead horse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無断", "Back": "without permission;without notice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無知", "Back": "ignorance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無茶", "Back": "absurd;unreasonable;excessive;rash;absurdity;nonsense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無茶苦茶", "Back": "confused;jumbled;mixed up;unreasonable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空しい", "Back": "vacant;futile;vain;void;empty;ineffective;lifeless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無念", "Back": "chagrin;regret", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無能", "Back": "inefficiency;incompetence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無闇に", "Back": "unreasonably;absurdly;recklessly;indiscreetly;at random", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無用", "Back": "useless;futility;needlessness;unnecessariness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "群がる", "Back": "to swarm;to gather", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無論", "Back": "of course;naturally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名産", "Back": "noted product", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名称", "Back": "name", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "命中", "Back": "a hit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名簿", "Back": "register of names", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名誉", "Back": "honor;credit;prestige", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明瞭", "Back": "clarity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明朗", "Back": "bright;clear;cheerful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目方", "Back": "weight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恵み", "Back": "blessing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恵む", "Back": "to bless;to show mercy to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目覚しい", "Back": "brilliant;splendid;striking;remarkable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目覚める", "Back": "to wake up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "召す", "Back": "to call;to send for;to put on;to wear;to take (a bath);to ride in;to buy;to eat;to drink;to catch (a", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雌", "Back": "female (animal)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滅茶苦茶", "Back": "absurd;unreasonable;excessive;messed up;spoiled;wreaked", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目付き", "Back": "look;expression of the eyes;eyes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滅亡", "Back": "downfall;ruin;collapse;destruction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愛でたい", "Back": "auspicious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目眩", "Back": "dizziness;giddiness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目盛", "Back": "scale;gradations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面会", "Back": "interview", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "免除", "Back": "exemption;exoneration;discharge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面する", "Back": "to face on;to look out on to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面目", "Back": "face;honour;reputation;prestige;dignity;credit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "設ける", "Back": "to create;to establish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申し入れる", "Back": "to propose;to suggest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申し込み", "Back": "application;entry;request;subscription;offer;proposal;overture;challenge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申出", "Back": "proposal;request;claim;report;notice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申し出る", "Back": "to report to;to tell;to suggest;to submit;to request;to make an offer;to come forward with informati", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申し分", "Back": "objection;shortcomings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盲点", "Back": "blind spot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "猛烈", "Back": "violent;vehement;rage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "藻掻く", "Back": "to struggle;to wriggle;to be impatient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目録", "Back": "catalogue;catalog;list", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目論見", "Back": "a plan;a scheme;a project;a program;intention;goal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "模型", "Back": "model;dummy;maquette", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "模索", "Back": "groping (for)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "若し", "Back": "if;in case;supposing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "若しかしたら", "Back": "perhaps;maybe;by some chance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "若しかして", "Back": "perhaps;possibly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "若しかすると", "Back": "perhaps;maybe;by some chance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "若しくは", "Back": "or;otherwise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "若しも", "Back": "if", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "齎らす", "Back": "to bring;to take;to bring about", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凭れる", "Back": "to lean against;to lean on;to recline on;to lie heavy (on the stomach)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "持ち", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;hold;charge;keep possession;in charge; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;wear;durability;life;draw; 3.&nbsp;&nbsp;usage (suff)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "持ち切り", "Back": "hot topic;talk of the town", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物体ない", "Back": "too good;more than one deserves;wasteful;sacrilegious;unworthy of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "以て", "Back": "with;by;by means of;because;in view of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "専ら", "Back": "wholly;solely;entirely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "持て成す", "Back": "to entertain;to make welcome", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "持てる", "Back": "to be well liked;to be popular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基", "Back": "basis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物置き", "Back": "storeroom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物好き", "Back": "curiosity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物足りない", "Back": "unsatisfied;unsatisfactory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "最早", "Back": "already;now", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "模範", "Back": "exemplar;exemplification;exemplum;model;example", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "模倣", "Back": "imitation;copying", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揉める", "Back": "to disagree;to dispute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腿", "Back": "thigh;femur", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "催す", "Back": "to hold (a meeting);to give (a dinner);to feel;to show signs of;to develop symptoms of;to feel (sick", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漏らす", "Back": "to let leak;to reveal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盛り上がる", "Back": "to rouse;to swell;to rise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漏る", "Back": "to leak;to run out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漏れる", "Back": "to leak out;to escape;to come through;to shine through;to filter out;to be omitted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脆い", "Back": "brittle;fragile;tender-hearted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "もろに", "Back": "completely;all the way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "問", "Back": "problem;question", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "矢", "Back": "arrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "哉", "Back": "question mark", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "喧しい", "Back": "noisy;strict;fussy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "野外", "Back": "fields;outskirts;open air;suburbs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軈て", "Back": "before long;soon;at length", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜行", "Back": "walking around at night;night train;night travel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役職", "Back": "post;managerial position;official position", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役立つ", "Back": "to be useful;to be helpful;to serve the purpose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役場", "Back": "town hall", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜具", "Back": "bedding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優", "Back": "gentle;affectionate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "屋敷", "Back": "mansion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "養う", "Back": "to rear;to maintain;to cultivate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "社", "Back": "Shinto shrine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "野心", "Back": "ambition;aspiration;designs;treachery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "易い", "Back": "easy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "安っぽい", "Back": "cheap-looking;tawdry;insignificant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休める", "Back": "to rest;to suspend;to give relief", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "野生", "Back": "wild", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "矢鱈に", "Back": "randomly;recklessly;blindly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜中", "Back": "all night;the whole night", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奴", "Back": "servant;fellow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やっ付ける", "Back": "to beat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "矢っ張り", "Back": "also;as I thought;still;in spite of;absolutely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "野党", "Back": "opposition party", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "病", "Back": "illness;disease", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "闇", "Back": "darkness;the dark;black-marketeering;dark;shady;illegal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "病む", "Back": "to fall ill;to be ill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "止むを得ない", "Back": "cannot be helped;unavoidable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "稍", "Back": "a little;partially;somewhat;a short time;a while", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ややこしい", "Back": "puzzling;tangled;complicated;complex", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遣り通す", "Back": "to carry through;to achieve;to complete", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やり遂げる", "Back": "to accomplish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遣る", "Back": "to do;to have sexual intercourse;to kill;to give (to inferiors&nbsp;&nbsp;animals&nbsp;&nbsp;etc.);to dispatch (a letter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "和らげる", "Back": "to soften;to moderate;to relieve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優位", "Back": "predominance;ascendancy;superiority", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憂鬱", "Back": "depression;melancholy;dejection;gloom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有益", "Back": "beneficial;profitable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優越", "Back": "supremacy;predominance;being superior to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勇敢", "Back": "bravery;heroism;gallantry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有機", "Back": "organic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夕暮れ", "Back": "evening;(evening) twilight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "融資", "Back": "financing;loan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有する", "Back": "to own;to be endowed with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "融通", "Back": "lending (money);accommodation;adaptability;versatility;finance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優勢", "Back": "superiority;superior power;predominance;preponderance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優先", "Back": "preference;priority", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誘導", "Back": "guidance;leading;induction;introduction;incitement;inducement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優美", "Back": "grace;refinement;elegance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有望", "Back": "good prospects;full of hope;promising", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遊牧", "Back": "nomadism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夕焼け", "Back": "sunset", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有力", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;influence;prominence; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;potent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幽霊", "Back": "ghost;specter;apparition;phantom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誘惑", "Back": "temptation;allurement;lure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揺さぶる", "Back": "to shake;to jolt;to rock;to swing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "茹でる", "Back": "to boil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゆとり", "Back": "reserve;affluence;room;time (to spare)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指差す", "Back": "to point at", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弓", "Back": "bow (and arrow)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揺らぐ", "Back": "to swing;to sway;to shake;to tremble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "緩む", "Back": "to become loose;to slacken", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "緩める", "Back": "to loosen;to slow down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "緩やか", "Back": "lenient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世", "Back": "world;society;age;generation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好い", "Back": "good", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要因", "Back": "primary factor;main cause", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溶液", "Back": "solution (liquid)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "用件", "Back": "business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "養護", "Back": "protection;nursing;protective care", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "用紙", "Back": "blank form", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "様式", "Back": "style;form;pattern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要する", "Back": "to demand;to require;to take", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要請", "Back": "claim;demand;request;application", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "養成", "Back": "training;development", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "様相", "Back": "aspect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "用品", "Back": "articles;supplies;parts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "洋風", "Back": "western style", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "用法", "Back": "directions;rules of use", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要望", "Back": "demand for;request", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余暇", "Back": "leisure;leisure time;spare time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予感", "Back": "presentiment;premonition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余興", "Back": "side show;entertainment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "預金", "Back": "deposit;bank account", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抑圧", "Back": "check;restraint;oppression;suppression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浴室", "Back": "bathroom;bath", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抑制", "Back": "suppression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欲深い", "Back": "greedy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欲望", "Back": "desire;appetite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寄こす", "Back": "to send;to forward", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "横綱", "Back": "sumo grand champion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "葦", "Back": "reed;bulrush", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "善し悪し", "Back": "good or bad;merits or demerits;quality;suitability", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予想", "Back": "expectation;anticipation;prediction;forecast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余所見", "Back": "looking away;looking aside", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余地", "Back": "place;room;margin;scope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "依って", "Back": "therefore;consequently;accordingly;because of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余程", "Back": "very;greatly;much;to a large extent;quite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "与党", "Back": "government party;(ruling) party in power;government", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呼び止める", "Back": "to challenge;to call somebody to halt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜更かし", "Back": "staying up late;keeping late hours;sitting up late at night;nighthawk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜更け", "Back": "late at night", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "読み上げる", "Back": "to read out loud (and clearly);to call a roll", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寄り掛かる", "Back": "to lean against;to recline on;to lean on;to rely on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宜しく", "Back": "well;properly;suitably;best regards;please remember me", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弱まる", "Back": "to abate;to weaken;to be emaciated;to be dejected;to be perplexed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弱める", "Back": "to weaken", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弱る", "Back": "to weaken;to be troubled;to be downcast;to be emaciated;to be dejected;to be perplexed;to impair", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "来場", "Back": "attendance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酪農", "Back": "dairy (farm)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落下", "Back": "fall;drop;come down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "楽観", "Back": "optimism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濫用", "Back": "abuse;misuse;misappropriation;using to excess", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "理屈", "Back": "theory;reason", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "利根", "Back": "intelligence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "利子", "Back": "interest (bank)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "利潤", "Back": "profit;returns", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "理性", "Back": "reason;sense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "利息", "Back": "interest (bank)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "立体", "Back": "solid body", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "立法", "Back": "legislation;lawmaking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "利点", "Back": "advantage;point in favor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "略語", "Back": "abbreviation;acronym", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "略奪", "Back": "pillage;plunder;looting;robbery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流", "Back": "styleof;method of;manner of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流通", "Back": "circulation of money or goods;flow of water or air;distribution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "了", "Back": "finish;completion;understanding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "料", "Back": "material;charge;rate;fee", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "領域", "Back": "area;domain;territory;field;region;regime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "了解", "Back": "comprehension;consent;understanding;roger (on the radio)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "領海", "Back": "territorial waters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "両極", "Back": "both extremities;north and south poles;positive and negative poles", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "良好", "Back": "favorable;satisfactory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "良識", "Back": "good sense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "良質", "Back": "good quality;superior quality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "了承", "Back": "acknowledgement;understanding (e.g. please be understanding of the mess during our renovation)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "良心", "Back": "conscience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "領地", "Back": "territory;dominion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "領土", "Back": "dominion;territory;possession", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "両立", "Back": "compatibility;coexistence;standing together", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "旅客", "Back": "passenger (transport)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "旅券", "Back": "passport", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "履歴", "Back": "personal history;background;career;log", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "理論", "Back": "theory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "輪", "Back": "counter for wheels and flowers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "林業", "Back": "forestry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "類似", "Back": "analogous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "類推", "Back": "analogy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷酷", "Back": "cruelty;coldheartedness;relentless;ruthless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷蔵", "Back": "cold storage;refrigeration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷淡", "Back": "coolness;indifference", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恋愛", "Back": "love;love-making;passion;emotion;affections", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連休", "Back": "consecutive holidays", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連日", "Back": "every day;prolonged", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連中", "Back": "colleagues;company;a lot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連帯", "Back": "solidarity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連邦", "Back": "commonwealth;federation of states", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連盟", "Back": "league;union;alliance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "老衰", "Back": "senility;senile decay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "朗読", "Back": "reading aloud;recitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浪費", "Back": "waste;extravagance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "労力", "Back": "labour;effort;toil;trouble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "碌な", "Back": "satisfactory;decent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "碌に", "Back": "well;enough;sufficient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "露骨", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;frank;blunt;plain;outspoken; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;conspicuous;open; 3.&nbsp;&nbsp;broad;suggestive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "論議", "Back": "discussion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "論理", "Back": "logic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "和", "Back": "sum;harmony;peace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "我がまま", "Back": "selfishness;egoism;wilfulness;disobedience;whim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "枠", "Back": "frame;slide", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "惑星", "Back": "planet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "技", "Back": "art;technique", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "態と", "Back": "on purpose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "態々", "Back": "expressly;specially;doing something especially rather than incidentally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煩わしい", "Back": "troublesome;annoying;complicated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "渡り鳥", "Back": "migratory bird;bird of passage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詫び", "Back": "apology", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "和風", "Back": "Japanese style", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "和文", "Back": "Japanese text;sentence in Japanese", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "藁", "Back": "straw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割合に", "Back": "comparatively", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割り当て", "Back": "allotment;assignment;allocation;quota;rationing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割り込む", "Back": "to cut in;to thrust oneself into;to wedge oneself in;to muscle in on;to interrupt;to disturb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割り算", "Back": "division (math)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割引き", "Back": "discount;reduction;rebate;tenths discounted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪者", "Back": "bad fellow;rascal;ruffian;scoundrel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アイデア", "Back": "idea", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アクセル", "Back": "accelerator", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アップ", "Back": "up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アプローチ", "Back": "approach (in golf)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アマチュア", "Back": "amateur", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アラブ", "Back": "Arab", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アルカリ", "Back": "alkali", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アルミ", "Back": "aluminum (Al);aluminium", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アワー", "Back": "hour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アンケート", "Back": "(fr:) (n) questionnaire (fr: enquete);survey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アンコール", "Back": "encore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "イエス", "Back": "Jesus;yes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インターチェンジ", "Back": "interchange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インターナショナル", "Back": "international", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インターフォン", "Back": "intercom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インテリ", "Back": "egghead;intelligentsia", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インフォメーション", "Back": "information", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インフレ", "Back": "inflation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ウェートレス", "Back": "waitress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "エアメール", "Back": "air mail", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "エレガント", "Back": "elegant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "エンジニア", "Back": "engineer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オーケー", "Back": "OK", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オートマチック", "Back": "automatic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オープン", "Back": "open", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オリエンテーション", "Back": "orientation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オレンジ", "Back": "an orange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オンライン", "Back": "on-line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カーペット", "Back": "carpet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カクテル", "Back": "cocktail", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カット", "Back": "cut;cutting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カテゴリー", "Back": "category", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カムバック", "Back": "comeback", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カメラマン", "Back": "cameraman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カルテ", "Back": "(de:) (n) clinical records (de: Karte)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ガイド", "Back": "tour guide", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カンニング", "Back": "cunning;cheat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ガイドブック", "Back": "guidebook", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ガレージ", "Back": "garage (at house)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "キャッチ", "Back": "catch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "キャリア", "Back": "career;career government employee", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "クイズ", "Back": "quiz", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "クラブ", "Back": "club;crab", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "クレーン", "Back": "crane", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "グラフ", "Back": "graph", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "グレー", "Back": "grey;gray", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コーナー", "Back": "corner", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゲスト", "Back": "guest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コマーシャル", "Back": "a commercial", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コミュニケーション", "Back": "communication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コンタクト", "Back": "contact;contact lens", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コメント", "Back": "comment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コンテスト", "Back": "contest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コントラスト", "Back": "contrast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コントロール", "Back": "control", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コンパス", "Back": "compass", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サイクル", "Back": "cycle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サイズ", "Back": "size", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サボる", "Back": "to be truant;to be idle;to sabotage by slowness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サンキュー", "Back": "thank you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サンタクロース", "Back": "Santa Claus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "シート", "Back": "seat;sheet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "システム", "Back": "system", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "シック", "Back": "chic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "シナリオ", "Back": "scenario", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ショー", "Back": "show", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ショック", "Back": "shock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジーパン", "Back": "jeans (lit: jeans pants);dungarees", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジャズ", "Back": "jazz", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジャンパー", "Back": "jacket;jumper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジャンプ", "Back": "jump", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジャンボ", "Back": "jumbo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジャンル", "Back": "genre", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スタジオ", "Back": "studio", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スチーム", "Back": "steam", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ストライキ", "Back": "strike", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ストレス", "Back": "stress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ストロー", "Back": "straw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ストロボ", "Back": "stroboscope (lit: strobo);strobe lamp;stroboscopic lamp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スピード", "Back": "speed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スプリング", "Back": "spring", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スペース", "Back": "space", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スポーツカー", "Back": "sports car", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スラックス", "Back": "slacks", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "セール", "Back": "sale", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "セクション", "Back": "section", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "セックス", "Back": "sexual intercourse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "セレモニー", "Back": "ceremony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "センス", "Back": "good sense (for music&nbsp;&nbsp;style&nbsp;&nbsp;tact&nbsp;&nbsp;etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゼリー", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;jelly; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;Jerry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ソース", "Back": "source", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ソックス", "Back": "socks", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ソロ", "Back": "solo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイトル", "Back": "title", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイピスト", "Back": "typist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイマー", "Back": "timer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイミング", "Back": "timing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイム", "Back": "time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイムリー", "Back": "timely;run-batted-in (baseball);RBI", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイヤ", "Back": "tire;tyre", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイル", "Back": "tile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タレント", "Back": "talent;star;personality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タワー", "Back": "tower", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダース", "Back": "dozen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダウン", "Back": "down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダブる", "Back": "to coincide (fall on the same day);to have two of something;to repeat a school year after failing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダンプ", "Back": "dump", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チームワーク", "Back": "teamwork", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チェンジ", "Back": "change", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チャイム", "Back": "chime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チャンネル", "Back": "a channel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ティッシュペーパー", "Back": "tissue paper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "テレックス", "Back": "telex;teletypewriter exchange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "データ", "Back": "data", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "デコレーション", "Back": "decoration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "デザート", "Back": "dessert", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "デザイン", "Back": "design", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "デッサン", "Back": "(fr:) (n) rough sketch (fr: dessin)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "デモンストレーション", "Back": "demonstration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "トーン", "Back": "tone", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "トラブル", "Back": "trouble (sometimes used as a verb)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "トランジスター", "Back": "transistor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ドライ", "Back": "dry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ドライクリーニング", "Back": "dry cleaning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ドライバー", "Back": "driver;screwdriver", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ドライブイン", "Back": "drive in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ドリル", "Back": "drill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ナイター", "Back": "game under lights (e.g. baseball) (lit: nighter);night game", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ナプキン", "Back": "napkin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ナンセンス", "Back": "nonsense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ニュー", "Back": "new", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ニュアンス", "Back": "nuance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ネガ", "Back": "(photographic) negative", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ノイローゼ", "Back": "(de:) (n) neurosis (de: Neurose)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ハンガー", "Back": "hangar;(coat) hanger;hunger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バー", "Back": "bar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バッジ", "Back": "badge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バット", "Back": "bat;vat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パジャマ", "Back": "pajamas;pyjamas", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パチンコ", "Back": "pachinko (Japanese pinball)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パトカー", "Back": "patrol car", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パンク", "Back": "1.&nbsp;&nbsp;(abbr) puncture;bursting; 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;punk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ヒント", "Back": "hint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ビールス", "Back": "virus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ビジネス", "Back": "business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ファイト", "Back": "fight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ファイル", "Back": "file", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ファン", "Back": "fan;fun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "フィルター", "Back": "(camera) filter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "フェリー", "Back": "ferry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "フォーム", "Back": "foam;form", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "フロント", "Back": "front", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ブーツ", "Back": "boots", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ブーム", "Back": "boom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ブザー", "Back": "buzzer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ブルー", "Back": "blue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ベース", "Back": "base;bass", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ベスト", "Back": "best;vest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ベストセラー", "Back": "best-seller", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ペア", "Back": "pair;pear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ホース", "Back": "hose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ホール", "Back": "hall;hole", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ボイコット", "Back": "boycott", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ボルト", "Back": "volt;bolt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ポーズ", "Back": "pause", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ポイント", "Back": "point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ポジション", "Back": "position", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ポット", "Back": "pot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ポンプ", "Back": "pump", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マーク", "Back": "mark", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マスコミ", "Back": "mass communication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マッサージ", "Back": "massage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ミスプリント", "Back": "misprint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ミセス", "Back": "Mrs.", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ミュージック", "Back": "music", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ミリ", "Back": "milli-;10^-3", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ムード", "Back": "mood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "メーカー", "Back": "maker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "メッセージ", "Back": "message", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "メディア", "Back": "media", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "メロディー", "Back": "melody", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "モーテル", "Back": "motel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "モニター", "Back": "(computer) monitor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ヤング", "Back": "young", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ユニーク", "Back": "unique", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ユニフォーム", "Back": "uniform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ライス", "Back": "rice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ラベル", "Back": "label", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ランプ", "Back": "lamp;ramp;headlight;light", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ルーズ", "Back": "loose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ルール", "Back": "rule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レース", "Back": "race;lace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レギュラー", "Back": "regular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レクリエーション", "Back": "recreation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レッスン", "Back": "lesson", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レディー", "Back": "lady", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レバー", "Back": "lever;liver", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レンジ", "Back": "range;stove", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レンタカー", "Back": "hire car (lit: rent-a-car)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レントゲン", "Back": "X-ray (lit: Roentgen)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ロープ", "Back": "rope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ローマ字", "Back": "romanization;Roman letters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ロマンチック", "Back": "romantic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ワット", "Back": "watt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{}]
